<article>
    <author>Sarah</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://savetheday.vote/">
        <end>1736</end>
        <start>1703</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>World-renowned writer/director Joss Whedon has returned to social media with a vengeance and a message that needs to be heard by everyone. Especially those who are apparently severely apathetic to the election this year. The director and creator knows all too well that we can&#226;&#128;&#153;t sit this election out and has recruited some of the biggest names in the entertainment industry to get his message out there. His Save the Day PAC is described as such: &#226;&#128;&#156;We are a short-form digital productions company dedicated to the idea that voting is a necessary and heroic act. That every voice in this wonderfully diverse nation should, and must, be heard. That the only thing that can save democracy is the act that defines it. We are committed to fighting the apathy, cynicism, and honest confusion that keeps citizens from using their vote. And to reminding an increasingly out-of-touch and compromised set of representatives that they are answerable to the people they were hired to serve.&#226;&#128;&#157; It&#226;&#128;&#153;s clear in the video that Donald Trump must be defeated for the good of all humanity, so it makes absolute sense that Whedon would use those who have played superheroes in his movies to get this very important message across. It&#226;&#128;&#153;s absolutely important that we all vote, not only for president, but also for legislators all the way down to the local level. This election defines not only who will lead the nation, but also who will sit on the Supreme Court, and as Whedon&#226;&#128;&#153;s video points out, it&#226;&#128;&#153;s a &#226;&#128;&#156;tipping point&#226;&#128;&#157; for the world. Sitting at home because you think both parties are equally as bad isn&#226;&#128;&#153;t only wrong, it&#226;&#128;&#153;s dangerous&#194;&#160;and allows that which we despise the most to gain power and control. Go here to visit Save the Day PAC, register to vote, and make sure your voice is heard. Watch the video here:  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>220</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>406</end>
        <start>221</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>449</end>
        <start>407</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>985</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1216</end>
        <start>986</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1529</end>
        <start>1217</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1702</end>
        <start>1530</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1790</end>
        <start>1703</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1812</end>
        <start>1791</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1813</end>
        <start>1813</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1814</end>
        <start>1814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>addicting-info</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>984</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </quote>
    <title>&#226;&#128;&#152;Avengers&#226;&#128;&#153; Director Launches EPIC Celebrity-Filled Superhero Effort To DEFEAT Trump (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/21/avengers-director-launches-epic-celebrity-filled-superhero-effort-to-defeat-trump-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>