<article>
    <author>Gary Chambers</author>
    <mainText>Terrorism seems to be producing more stupidity than fear, I keep hearing the word suspect or suspected every time a bomb goes off in America or when the words Allahu&#160;Akbar is&#160;screamed out&#160;when a mass shooting takes place. I get to listen to a New York Mayor tell the nation that the bomb blast had no relation to the bomb blast in New Jersey on the same day. I guess the FBI could learn a lot from this&#160;Mayor. A reporter on Fox News says the&#160;bomb&#160; could have been a pressure cooker that someone put in the garbage can by mistake.&#160;The media will put&#160;on experts and have many opinions to tell all about something that needs no explanation except just one. These Muslims are going to kill us unless we kill them first. When&#160;law enforcement catches&#160;or kills one I could care less about his&#160;personal history that the media always uses to make a good story to tell. The only thing I care about is punishing&#160;him&#160;without the pleasure of giving him a life sentence in a prison where he gets to choose his food from a Muslim menu, free medical service, recreation facilities,&#160;&#160;a TV to watch his friends&#160;terrorist activities all over the world and a Quran with a prayer rug. Terrorists should be tried by law within thirty days after their capture and sentenced&#160; in the same time frame. I am just a simple man and I would rather form my own opinion than letting the media doing it for me. After all, who wants to be stupid? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>221</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>409</end>
        <start>222</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>653</end>
        <start>410</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>715</end>
        <start>654</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1163</end>
        <start>716</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1412</end>
        <start>1164</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1413</end>
        <start>1413</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <title>No Mercy for the Terrorists</title>
    <uri>http://ipatriot.com/no-mercy-terrorirsts/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>