<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://nypost.com/2016/09/18/inside-the-scramble-to-cover-up-clintons-private-email-server/">
        <end>2141</end>
        <start>2063</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>The scramble to cover-up the Hillary email scandal has come to light. The Platte River IT executives were not ignorant to what was going on. As subcontractors, they tried to distance themselves from what was going on. One executive call it; Hillary&#8217;s cover-up operation. It is astonishing that the FBI and the whole of the Justice Department were unable (unwilling) to see this. Read more below.  As Written By Isabel Vincent and Melissa Klein for The New York Post: Computers from China and Russia tried to attack Hillary Clinton&#8217;s private e-mail server, according to never-released e-mails from the Denver company that set up and maintained the system. And other internal e-mails show the IT executives fretted about being ordered to purge e-mails and scrambled to distance themselves from what they believed was the former first lady &#8220;covering up some shaddy [shady] s- -t.&#8221; In a gallows-humor message, one called it &#8220;Hillary&#8217;s coverup operation.&#8221; The FBI in July chastised Clinton and her aides over the use of the private server, saying, &#8220;They were extremely careless in their handling of very sensitive, highly classified information.&#8221; But the agency declined to recommend charges. The FBI report noted there were many hacking attempts into the system, both while Clinton was secretary of state and afterward when Platte River Networks took over the administration of the home server. The agency said none had been successful, and it never named the hackers or their points of origin. But multiple internal Platte River e-mails reviewed by The Post show that computers in China tried on three occasions in 2014 to log into Clinton&#8217;s server and a computer in Russia tried once in 2013. The internal communications also revealed how the execs belatedly tightened security on Clinton&#8217;s now-controversial home server and frantically sought to &#8220;cover our asses&#8221; when news broke that the former secretary of state&#8217;s communications were deleted. &#8220;Any chance you found an old e-mail with their directives to cut the backups back in Oct&#8208;-Feb? . . . Full Story Here: Inside the scramble to cover up Clinton&#8217;s private email server | New York Post</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>395</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>396</end>
        <start>396</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>466</end>
        <start>397</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>654</end>
        <start>467</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>877</end>
        <start>655</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>950</end>
        <start>878</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1187</end>
        <start>951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1490</end>
        <start>1188</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1690</end>
        <start>1491</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1944</end>
        <start>1691</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2045</end>
        <start>1945</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2062</end>
        <start>2046</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2141</end>
        <start>2063</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>876</end>
        <start>838</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>949</end>
        <start>921</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1140</end>
        <start>1044</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1861</end>
        <start>1846</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2141</end>
        <start>2046</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Inside the cover up of Hillary&#8217;s email server</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/inside-the-cover-up-of-hillarys-email-server/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>