<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <mainText>They don&#8217;t call CNN the Clinton News Network for nothing. They&#8217;re there to defend the presidential candidate at all costs and not let any inconvenient facts get in the way. CNN host Chris Cuomo &#8211; the New York Governor&#8217;s little brother &#8211; got into a tense exchange with one of Donald Trump&#8217;s advisers Boris Epshteyn. Cuomo argued that Trump should come clean with the birther issue, just as Hillary Clinton owned up to her private server issue. &#8220;With Hillary Clinton, she had to own the server thing,&#8221; Cuomo said. &#8220;It was wrong. We heard from all the people around her that it was wrong, she shouldn&#8217;t have done it, it was poorly thought out. It wasn&#8217;t enough. Why?&#8221; Epshteyn responded that they&#8217;re not the same thing. &#8220;And Hillary Clinton &#8212; there&#8217;s no equivalency. Hillary Clinton did something illegal. She broke the law.&#8221; They continued: Chris Cuomo: She did not do anything illegal. Boris Epshteyn: Yes, she did. Cuomo: James Comey&#8217;s a liar, too? Epshteyn: He said she shouldn&#8217;t be prosecuted. He did say she acted carelessly, and as a lawyer, if you look at all the particulars of bringing that case, there was a case to bring. And he said so, too. Cuomo: No, he didn&#8217;t. He said there&#8217;s no case that could be brought, there&#8217;s nothing prosecutable about it. He just said it in his report. He said it wasn&#8217;t a close call. Never mind the fact that even the FBI Director himself stated that it is a &#8220;felony to mishandle classified information either intentionally or in a grossly negligent way, or a second statute making it a misdemeanor to knowingly remove classified information from appropriate systems or storage facilities.&#8221; Isn&#8217;t that exactly what Hillary Clinton did? Comey even said that she was &#8220;extremely careless&#8221; &#8211; in other words, grossly negligent &#8211; in her handling of classified information. And everyone knows that she had some 13 different mobile devices in addition to her private home server, which had on it classified information.   The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>172</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>314</end>
        <start>173</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>315</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>838</end>
        <start>665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>884</end>
        <start>839</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>914</end>
        <start>885</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>948</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1151</end>
        <start>949</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1322</end>
        <start>1152</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1629</end>
        <start>1323</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1950</end>
        <start>1630</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1951</end>
        <start>1951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1952</end>
        <start>1952</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2098</end>
        <start>1953</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2172</end>
        <start>2099</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>498</end>
        <start>444</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>663</end>
        <start>513</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>821</end>
        <start>718</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1628</end>
        <start>1399</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1723</end>
        <start>1705</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2134</end>
        <start>2122</start>
    </quote>
    <title>CNN on Hillary&#8217;s Email Crimes: &#8220;She Did NOT do ANYTHING Illegal&#8221; [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36821/cnn-on-hillarys-email-crimes-she-did-not-do-anything-illegal-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>