<article>
    <author>Mohamed Hamada</author>
    <mainText>Scene number one &#8211;&#160;Cairo, Egypt: I am packing my luggage. At last, I am fulfilling my dream. I am ready for a long journey to a developed country that respects science and scientists. I am ready to join the developed world. Scene number two &#8211;&#160;New York, America: I feel shaky. I am stepping on the American land for the first time. I am joyful. &#160;I&#8217;m full of euphoria, and I am worried. It&#8217;s a new life. I&#8217;m looking for a happy future, but am still scared. &#160;What if all of this is just a dream and is not really happening? Scene number three &#8211;&#160;Louisville, Kentucky: I am not dreaming &#8211; it&#8217;s really happening. I am in a class in America for the first time. I pinched myself to make sure I&#8217;m awake. Scene number four &#8211;&#160;a&#160;couple of weeks since my arrival: I&#8217;m having an awful nightmare. I&#8217;m walking out of the classroom to find all of the&#160;faculty, the staff, and the students standing in a line. At the front of the line, there is a small TV in the Secretary&#8217;s office. A&#160;major terrorist attack has occurred. I wish it&#8217;s not true, and that it&#8217;s just a bad dream. I am hoping to wake up. However, It was true, I was awake, it was really happening. Scene number five &#8211;&#160;I take my spot in the line waiting and my heart is racing: What if they were Muslims? Please God, don&#8217;t let them be Muslims. The news came, the truth was hard. They were Muslims and worse, the leader is Egyptian. I am speechless. I covered my face with my hands from the shame and I tried to walk away. An American professor tapped on my back with sympathy. &#160;An older American student whispered in my ear: &#8220;Take care of yourself. Some people might hurt you in blind retaliation.&#8221; I didn&#8217;t have a car then, and an&#160;American girl who I hardly knew offered to drive me home. I came here to study and work in a developed country. Later, I realized that the biggest gain is living among civilized people. Scene number six &#8211;&#160;many weeks later, I am in the airport: I am being harassed in the airports by the security every time I try to fly. Every time, I am picked randomly for a body search. This time, after every kind of search was performed on me and I was about to step in the airplane with my carry-on bag, a security person told me: &#8221;Sir, you can&#8217;t have this bag with you on the airplane.&#8221; &#160;I screamed: &#8221;I have the right to have a carry-on item!&#8221; &#160;He repeated in a begging tone: &#8220;Please sir, you can&#8217;t have this bag with you.&#8221; The worries and the fear in his eyes quelled my anger. I gave him the bag. I murmured: &#8220;What is some harassment? It&#8217;s a very small sacrifice compared to what was paid by those who lost their lives defending this country.&#8221;  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>32</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>223</end>
        <start>33</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>261</end>
        <start>224</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>520</end>
        <start>262</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>563</end>
        <start>521</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>694</end>
        <start>564</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>750</end>
        <start>695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1140</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1219</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1373</end>
        <start>1220</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1731</end>
        <start>1374</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1859</end>
        <start>1732</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1917</end>
        <start>1860</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2387</end>
        <start>1918</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2609</end>
        <start>2388</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2610</end>
        <start>2610</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2756</end>
        <start>2611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2830</end>
        <start>2757</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1639</end>
        <start>1568</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2386</end>
        <start>2341</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2608</end>
        <start>2476</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2792</end>
        <start>2780</start>
    </quote>
    <title>My Dream: Perspective of 9/11 From an Egyptian-born American</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36853/my-dream-perspective-of-911-from-an-egyptian-born-american/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>