<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.breitbart.com/radio/2016/09/20/caddell-ghw-bush-endorsement-hillary-clinton-establishment-protection-racket/">
        <end>1734</end>
        <start>1641</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>When&#160;George H.W. Bush endorsed Hillary Clinton, quite a few people stumbled in their tracks. The progressives see this as a justification of their agenda and a feather in the cap of their candidate. The conservatives see it as a betrayal and a mystery. Pat Caddell has dug up the root of the&#160;problem. It is old fashioned protection of the inside the beltway elite. Trump and Sanders have led the revolution, so their power base is endangered. &#160;Read and then click the link at the bottom of the post and listen!!  As Written By Dan Riehl for Breitbart: Long-time Democratic pollster Pat Caddell joinedBreitbart News DailySiriusXM host Alex Marlow on Tuesday to discuss recent polling, as well as news that former President George H.W. Bush may be voting for Democrat Hillary Clinton. &#8220;This is a protection racket here, and they have never been under greater threat,&#8221; said Caddell, referencing the candidacy of GOP nominee Donald Trump. &#8220;It&#8217;s not surprising in a way,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;We misunderstand that this Trump thing is not so much an ideological contest, even a partisan contest. It&#8217;s really an insurgency against the political class by the people. That&#8217;s why both Bernie Sanders and Trump did so well&#8221; in their respective primaries. Added Caddell, &#8220;Behind closed doors, what you have is a sense of an alliance,&#8221; pointing out that while one party may be up and the other down at times, they still &#8220;eat at the same trough&#8221; in Washington. Caddell went on to discuss recent polling, as well as what to expect going forward. Breitbart News Daily airs on SiriusXM Patriot 125 weekdays from 6:00 a.m.&#160;to 9:00 a.m.&#160;Eastern&#8230;.. Full Story Here: Caddell: George H.W. Bush Endorsement of Hillary Clinton Is Establishment &#8216;Protection Racket&#8217;</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>511</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>512</end>
        <start>512</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>551</end>
        <start>513</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>934</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1238</end>
        <start>935</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1441</end>
        <start>1239</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1525</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1623</end>
        <start>1526</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1640</end>
        <start>1624</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1734</end>
        <start>1641</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>864</end>
        <start>784</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>965</end>
        <start>936</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1206</end>
        <start>982</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1316</end>
        <start>1255</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1425</end>
        <start>1403</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1734</end>
        <start>1624</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Caddell: What the George H.W. Bush endorsement of Hillary REALLY means</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/caddell-what-the-george-h-w-bush-endorsement-of-hillary-really-means/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>