<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://2lv0hm3wvpix464wwy2zh7d1.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/george-h.w.-bush-hillary-clinton.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/exclusive-george-hw-bush-to-vote-for-hillary-228395?platform=hootsuite">
        <end>927</end>
        <start>906</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/exclusive-george-hw-bush-to-vote-for-hillary-228395?platform=hootsuite">
        <end>1086</end>
        <start>1057</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>It definitely wouldn&#8217;t be all that surprising if George H.W. Bush is voting for Hillary Clinton. After all, his son Jeb didn&#8217;t do all that well during the primary campaign, and in a show of opposition to Donald Trump, no one in the Bush clan showed up at the Republican National Convention for Trump&#8217;s coronation. The Bushes themselves have remained mum on the subject of whom they&#8217;re voting for. In fact, they&#8217;ve pretty much stayed out of the presidential race altogether. But one insider says the elder Bush of 92 years will be casting his vote for the Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton. That insider is one of the late Robert F. Kennedy&#8217;s daughters, Kathleen Hartington Kennedy Townsend. She is a former Democratic lieutenant governor of Maryland. On Monday, she posted a picture of her shaking hands with Bill Clinton&#8217;s predecessor with the caption: &#8220;The President told me he&#8217;s voting for Hillary!!&#8221;  According to Politico, Kennedy Townsend was visiting with the former President at his Maine summer home on Walker&#8217;s Point in Kennebunkport. Later in a phone interview with Politico, the Kennedy daughter confirmed, &#8220;That&#8217;s what he said.&#8221; But when pressed about it, a spokesman for Bush would neither confirm nor deny. In an email to Politico, Jim McGrath wrote, &#8220;The vote President Bush will cast as a private citizen in some 50 days will be just that: a private vote cast in some 50 days. He is not commenting on the presidential race in the interim.&#8221; Politico noted that George H.W. Bush wouldn&#8217;t be the first from his or his son&#8217;s administration to be voting for Hillary &#8211; or at least not voting for the Donald: &#8220;Many former GOP officials from both Bush administrations have also announced their support for Clinton over Trump, including national security adviser Brent Scowcroft and former Commerce Secretary Carlos Gutierrez.&#8221; &#160;  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>313</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>473</end>
        <start>314</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>590</end>
        <start>474</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>591</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>904</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>905</end>
        <start>905</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1045</end>
        <start>906</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1142</end>
        <start>1046</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1457</end>
        <start>1143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1836</end>
        <start>1458</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1838</end>
        <start>1837</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1839</end>
        <start>1839</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1985</end>
        <start>1840</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2059</end>
        <start>1986</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>903</end>
        <start>856</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1141</end>
        <start>1121</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1456</end>
        <start>1268</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1835</end>
        <start>1621</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2021</end>
        <start>2009</start>
    </quote>
    <title>George H.W. Bush Says he&#8217;s Voting for HILLARY?!</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36903/george-h-w-bush-says-hes-voting-for-hillary/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>