<article>
    <author>Jay Guy</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://thehill.com/policy/national-security/296680-house-panel-probes-web-rumor-on-clinton-emails">
        <end>1592</end>
        <start>1566</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThingsHillaryGoogles?src=hash">
        <end>2867</end>
        <start>2846</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="https://t.co/P41uwzYWAD">
        <end>2893</end>
        <start>2867</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump">
        <end>2909</end>
        <start>2893</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="https://twitter.com/bocavista2016/status/778495447543455744">
        <end>2958</end>
        <start>2940</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>In a day and age when government&#160;and media are larger than ever, an America-loving citizen has discovered what the Department of Justice and mainstream media have been unable (or unwillingly) to un-earth: Proof that Hillary &#160;Clinton conspired to cover up her &#8220;un-wise&#8221; use of a private server and email scandal. Through the power of social media, a Twitter user @GOPPollAnalyst has pieced together compelling evidence that has reached the House Oversight Committee who have begun a new investigation. Paul Combetta, the IT specialist hired by Hillary Clinton during her time as Secretary of State, allegedly solicited advice on how to remove Hillary&#8217;s name from classified emails. He made his requests from the public at large through the popular message board Reddit under the screen name &#8220;stonetear&#8221; throughout the summer and fall of 2014 and left more than a few definitive breadcrumbs. In his requests for help from the public at large, Combetta asked for technical advice on how to save or delete old emails as well as how to remove email addresses of an &#8220;Unamed VIP Client&#8221; from email servers and archives. &#8220;Hello all,&#8221; one of the posts begins. &#8220;I may be facing a very interesting situation where I need to strip out a VIP&#8217;s (VERY VIP) email address from a bunch of archived email that I have both in a live Exchange mailbox, as well as a PST file. Basically, they don&#8217;t want the VIP&#8217;s email address exposed to anyone. &#8230; Does anyone have experience with something like this, and/or suggestions on how this might be accomplished?&#8221; The House Oversight Committee has begun an investigation and has asked Reddit to save all relevant posts and data. Where that investigation goes is unclear but what is clear is that the American citizenry has uncovered what the crooked media and politicians have attempted to cover-up and have been unwilling to publish: proof of Hillary&#8217;s Clinton&#8217;s criminal activity. The investigation will likely pivot based on a very simple question: is the screen name &#8220;stonetear&#8221; definitively Combetta? In not, the evidence is circumstantial. If so, the proof is indisputable and ties a direct line between Hillary Clinton and a clearly illegal cover-up. To support the argument that &#8220;stonetear&#8221; is in fact Hillary Clinton&#8217;s IT specialist, @GOPPollAnalyst has unearthed the following connections: This story has not been widely reported and likely will not as media outlets have little incentive to highlight an average American doing their job for them.&#160;As word of this discovery spreads and the evidence presented throughout this post is presented to the House Oversight Committee, the work of the American people, both as investigators like @GOPPollAnalyst and as citizen-journalists like the authors here at IPatriot, will not remain silent. "How to delete an IT guy who uses Reddit and make it look like an accident"#ThingsHillaryGooglespic.twitter.com/P41uwzYWAD@realDonaldTrump &#8212; Boca Vista (@bocavista2016) September 21, 2016  &#160; &#160; </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>500</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>889</end>
        <start>501</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1112</end>
        <start>890</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1535</end>
        <start>1113</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1904</end>
        <start>1536</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2179</end>
        <start>1905</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2321</end>
        <start>2180</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2770</end>
        <start>2322</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2909</end>
        <start>2771</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2958</end>
        <start>2910</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2959</end>
        <start>2959</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2961</end>
        <start>2960</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2963</end>
        <start>2962</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2964</end>
        <start>2964</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>267</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>800</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>1061</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1124</end>
        <start>1114</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1534</end>
        <start>1152</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>800</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>800</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2958</end>
        <start>2771</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Proof of Hillary&#8217;s Cover-Up Discovered by Citizen-Journalist!</title>
    <uri>http://ipatriot.com/proof-hillarys-cover-discovered-citizen-journalist/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>