<article>
    <author>Onan Coca</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://constitution.com/hypocrite-hillary-wants-leave-defenseless/">
        <end>2144</end>
        <start>2098</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>&#8220;I really support everything President Obama said he would do through regulation on guns but we&#8217;re going to start the very first day and tackle the gun lobby.&#8221;&#160;&#8211; Hillary Clinton on MSNBC, 4/25/16 There are those who believe that the 2016 presidential election is a once in a generation, existential kind of national election. These folks notice all of the dangers we face and worry that depending on how the vote falls this November, we may soon be a very different nation than we&#8217;ve been. I&#8217;m not sure I fit on this worrisome boat, but I do believe that our dearest rights and freedoms are in danger today. The Left has developed a fascist streak unlike any we&#8217;ve seen previously in American history, and they believe it to be their duty to destroy our liberty&#8230; for our own good, of course. &#8220;The Supreme Court is wrong on the Second Amendment. And I am going to make that case every chance I get.&#8221;&#160;&#8211; Hillary Clinton, The Free Beacon, 10/1/15 Into this caustic climate comes the NRA, an organization wholly devoted to defending the 2nd&#160;Amendment from the gun-grabbing left. The NRA believes that if elected president, Hillary Clinton would do everything in her power to undermine and repeal the 2nd&#160;Amendment. Because of this, they are working hard to unmask her as the anti-freedom fascist she really is. Their latest ad paints a disturbing picture, reminding all Americans what is really at stake in the upcoming election.  This is the second in the &#8220;Don&#8217;t Let Hillary Leave You Defenseless&#8221; series. The previous ad covered the disgusting hypocrisy of Clinton&#8217;s anti-gun position. Here&#8217;s a woman who has lived the last 30+ years of her life surrounded by men with firearms, yet she has the audacity to tell law abiding American citizens that they shouldn&#8217;t have the right to use the same tool to defend their families? If it wasn&#8217;t such a serious topic, it&#8217;d be laughable. &#8220;When it comes to guns, we have just too many guns.&#8221;&#8212; Hillary Clinton, USA Today, 4/20/2016  In November, you can actively defend the Bill of Rights and the Constitution. All you have to do is vote AGAINST Hillary Clinton. Reposted With Permission From Constitution.com  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>195</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>489</end>
        <start>196</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>791</end>
        <start>490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>942</end>
        <start>792</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1073</end>
        <start>943</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1305</end>
        <start>1074</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1424</end>
        <start>1306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1425</end>
        <start>1425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1501</end>
        <start>1426</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1820</end>
        <start>1502</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1874</end>
        <start>1821</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1966</end>
        <start>1875</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1967</end>
        <start>1967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2097</end>
        <start>1968</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2144</end>
        <start>2098</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2145</end>
        <start>2145</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2291</end>
        <start>2146</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2365</end>
        <start>2292</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>158</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>897</end>
        <start>793</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1492</end>
        <start>1453</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1926</end>
        <start>1876</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2327</end>
        <start>2315</start>
    </quote>
    <title>The Utter HYPOCRISY of Hillary&#8217;s Anti-Gun Policies [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36946/the-utter-hypocrisy-of-hillarys-anti-gun-policies-video/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>