<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <hyperlink href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-politics/wp/2016/09/21/clinton-asks-why-she-isnt-beating-trump-by-50-points/">
        <end>1196</end>
        <start>1173</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Liberals in the media and the political arena thought that Hillary Clinton&#8217;s victory was in the bag. The rest of the campaign was a mere formality in order for her to make the White House her residence once again. Her campaign&#8217;s plan was to lay low, out of the spotlight, make little to no contact with the press, and just let Donald Trump do all the talking and hopefully keep his foot in his mouth to draw all the media attention. But now that the post-DNC honeymoon is over, they have to come back to reality and see that the election isn&#8217;t over, and that they had grossly underestimated Donald Trump and his campaign. Add to that Hillary&#8217;s frequent, inconvenient health episodes, and now even some Democrats are talking about a &#8220;Plan B.&#8221; For the past few weeks, the poll numbers have closed in, with Donald Trump taking the lead in several key battleground states. Now, even Hillary is asking why she isn&#8217;t &#8220;50 points ahead&#8221; of Trump? At a campaign event in Las Vegas, Hillary video conferenced in to address the Labor International Union of North America. While she was talking about &#8220;investing in infrastructure, raising the minimum wage, and collective bargaining,&#8221; she raised the question: &#8220;Having said all this, &#8216;Why aren&#8217;t I 50 points ahead?&#8217; you might ask? Well, the choice for working families has never been clearer. I need your help to get Donald Trump&#8217;s record out to everybody. Nobody should be fooled.&#8221; At another point in her speech, she encouraged her supporters to &#8220;stage an intervention&#8221; if they know anyone who supports Trump. &#8220;If you do know somebody who might be voting for Trump, stage an intervention,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Try to talk some sense into them. Lay out the facts. The facts are on our side, about what I&#8217;ve done versus what he&#8217;s done. Remember, friends don&#8217;t let friends vote for Trump.&#8221;  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>213</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>432</end>
        <start>214</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>741</end>
        <start>433</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>868</end>
        <start>742</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>938</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1197</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1198</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1816</end>
        <start>1420</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1817</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1963</end>
        <start>1818</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2037</end>
        <start>1964</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>740</end>
        <start>733</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>927</end>
        <start>912</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1171</end>
        <start>1090</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1418</end>
        <start>1199</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1507</end>
        <start>1486</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1627</end>
        <start>1550</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1815</end>
        <start>1640</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1198</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1999</end>
        <start>1987</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Hillary Wants to Know: &#8220;Why Aren&#8217;t I 50 Points Ahead?&#8221;</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36936/hillary-wants-to-know-why-arent-i-50-points-ahead/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>