<article>
    <author>Tim Brown</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/john-brennan-obamas-muslim-convert-stooge-jihad/">
        <end>80</end>
        <start>40</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://edition.cnn.com/2016/09/15/politics/john-brennan-cia-communist-vote/">
        <end>93</end>
        <start>85</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/?s=communist+party">
        <end>138</end>
        <start>123</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/congressman-frank-wolf-cia-employee-who-refused-to-sign-non-disclosure-agreement-on-benghazi-suspended/">
        <end>2308</end>
        <start>2224</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/cia-director-john-brennan-alleged-to-have-sent-letter-to-benghazi-survivors-telling-them-to-talk-to-congress-but-its-classified/">
        <end>2388</end>
        <start>2310</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/former-cia-operative-michael-scheuer-cia-director-john-brennan-is-a-bully-of-epic-dimensions/">
        <end>2409</end>
        <start>2393</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/john-brennan-sworn-in-on-constitution-without-bill-of-rights-not-bible/">
        <end>2623</end>
        <start>2526</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/john-brennan-gets-confirmation-but-has-most-no-votes-in-history/">
        <end>2722</end>
        <start>2659</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thurgood_Marshall_United_States_Courthouse">
        <end>2908</end>
        <start>2885</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manhattan">
        <end>2921</end>
        <start>2912</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smith_Act">
        <end>3008</end>
        <start>3004</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_G._Thompson">
        <end>3117</end>
        <start>3099</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second_World_War">
        <end>3163</end>
        <start>3147</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contempt_of_court">
        <end>3294</end>
        <start>3277</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dennis_v._United_States">
        <end>3443</end>
        <start>3420</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smith_Act">
        <end>3683</end>
        <start>3679</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claudia_Jones">
        <end>3735</end>
        <start>3722</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Gurley_Flynn">
        <end>3762</end>
        <start>3740</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://freedomoutpost.com/?s=cold%20war">
        <end>4064</end>
        <start>4056</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Barack Hussein Obama Soetoro Sobarkah&#8217;s&#160;Muslim convert CIA Director John Brennan&#160;has admitted to giving his support to the Communist Party in the 1976 election. Last week, during the Congressional Black Caucus Foundation&#8217;s annual conference, Brennan&#160;admitted&#160;that he was asked if he had &#8220;ever worked with or for a group that was dedicated to overthrowing the US&#8221; during his first polygraph test to enter the Central Intelligence Agency. &#8220;I froze,&#8221; Brennan said. &#8220;This was back in 1980, and I thought back to a previous election where I voted, and I voted for the Communist Party candidate.&#8221; Claiming that he believed the Constitution protected free speech, he said he decided to answer truthfully. &#8220;We&#8217;ve all had indiscretions in our past,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I would not be up here if that was disqualifying.&#8221; &#8220;I froze, because I was getting so close to coming into CIA and said, &#8216;OK, here&#8217;s the choice, John. You can deny that, and the machine is probably going to go, you know, wacko, or I can acknowledge it and see what happens,'&#8221; Brennan said. The question Brennan was asked came from the 1940 Smith Act, which &#8220;prohibit[ed] certain subversive activities,&#8221; among those were overthrow of the US Government by force or violence. Thus the question that is routinely asked is, &#8220;Have you EVER advocated (either directly or indirectly) the overthrow of any government by force or violence?&#8221; &#8220;I said I was neither Democratic nor Republican, but it was my way, as I was going to college, of signaling my unhappiness with the system, and the need for change,&#8221; Bennan added. &#8220;I said I&#8217;m not a member of the Communist Party, so the polygrapher looked at me and said, &#8216;OK,&#8217; and when I was finished with the polygraph and I left and said, &#8216;Well, I&#8217;m screwed.'&#8221; Brennan then attempted to put the people to sleep regarding their freedoms by stating, &#8220;So if back in 1980, John Brennan was allowed to say, &#8216;I voted for the&#160;Communist Party&#160;with Gus Hall&#8217; &#8230; and still got through, rest assured that your rights and your expressions and your freedom of speech as Americans is something that&#8217;s not going to be disqualifying of you as you pursue a career in government.&#8221; It&#8217;s interesting that Mr. Brennan would make such a statement considering the&#160;CIA suspended an employee who refused to sign a non-disclosure agreement on Benghazi,&#160;wanted to allow Benghazi survivors to talk to Congress, but kept it classified, is&#160;known as a bully, and has continued to help aid America&#8217;s enemies in the Middle East. We could even point to the fact that man would&#160;not even be sworn in on a Bible, but rather a copy of the Constitution without the Bill of Rights&#160;and that was only after he had the&#160;largest number of votes against his confirmation in our history. Between 1950 and 1957, many Communist Party members were indicted and convicted for advocating Communism. According to Wikipedia: After a ten-month trial at the&#160;Foley Square Courthouse&#160;in&#160;Manhattan, eleven leaders of the Communist Party were convicted under the Smith Act in 1949.[50]&#160;Ten defendants received sentences of five years and $10,000 fines. An eleventh defendant,&#160;Robert G. Thompson, a distinguished hero of the&#160;Second World War, was sentenced to three years in consideration of his military record. The five defense attorneys were cited for&#160;contempt of court&#160;and given prison sentences. Those convicted appealed the verdicts, and the Supreme Court upheld their convictions in 1951 in&#160;Dennis v. United States&#160;in a 6-2 decision. Following that decision, the DOJ prosecuted dozens of cases.&#160;In total, by May 1956, another 131 communists were indicted, of whom 98 were convicted, nine acquitted, while juries brought no verdict in the other cases.[51]&#160;Other party leaders indicted included&#160;Claudia Jones&#160;and&#160;Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, a founding member of the ACLU. However, June 17, 1957, Yates v. United States held unconstitutional the convictions of numerous party leaders in a ruling that &#8220;distinguished between advocacy of an idea for incitement and the teaching of an idea as a concept.&#8221; However, consider that that new&#160;Cold War, which has always been going on despite what the media has presented to us, is brewing and should anyone be surprised the Brennan, Obama and other Communist/Islamist ideologists are in positions of power? And do you really think they are not out to silence your opposition to you? If you do, then you are a part of the problem.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>160</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>436</end>
        <start>161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>590</end>
        <start>437</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>697</end>
        <start>591</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>801</end>
        <start>698</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1040</end>
        <start>802</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1381</end>
        <start>1041</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1744</end>
        <start>1382</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2145</end>
        <start>1745</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2723</end>
        <start>2146</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2853</end>
        <start>2724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3462</end>
        <start>2854</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3794</end>
        <start>3463</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4023</end>
        <start>3795</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4392</end>
        <start>4024</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4393</end>
        <start>4393</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4539</end>
        <start>4394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4613</end>
        <start>4540</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>361</end>
        <start>288</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>446</end>
        <start>438</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>589</end>
        <start>463</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>739</end>
        <start>699</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>800</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1025</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1152</end>
        <start>1109</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1380</end>
        <start>1271</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1546</end>
        <start>1383</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1743</end>
        <start>1563</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2144</end>
        <start>1833</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>4022</end>
        <start>3924</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>3794</end>
        <start>2854</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>4575</end>
        <start>4563</start>
    </quote>
    <title>CIA Director John Brennan Confesses Support for COMMUNIST Party</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37009/cia-director-john-brennan-confesses-support-for-communist-party/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>