<article>
    <author>100% FED Up</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://100percentfedup.com/shocking-video-is-hillarys-episode-heat-related-or-something-else-video/">
        <end>559</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>The Drudge Report has gained access to the rules for the upcoming Mega-Debate between Hillary and Trump. Hillary&#8217;s always angling for an advantage, and when it comes to the mainstream media, Hillary usually gets exactly what she wants. It looks like she&#8217;ll get a custom podium to help her with the height advantage, but when it comes to coughing up a lung, Hillary&#8217;s on her own. Let&#8217;s hope for Hillary&#8217;s sake, she&#8217;s able to keep the guy with the diazinon pen close to the stage in case &#8220;unfit to run for office Hillary&#8221; has another &#8220;pneumonia-related incident&#8221; like the one on 911&#8230;  DEBATE RULES: NO COUGHING BREAKS **Exclusive** Fri Sep 23 2016 11:30:40 ET If presidential hopeful Hillary Clinton slips into a coughing fit or any other medical crisis during Monday&#8217;s high-stakes debate, she will have to power through, the DRUDGE REPORT has learned! &#8220;There are no commercial breaks,&#8221; a commission source explains. &#8220;Period.&#8221; Debate moderator Lester Holt does not have the authority to cut away from the stage during the epic 90-minute showdown. And microphone audio for either of the candidates is not to be manipulated. Clinton has experienced severe coughing episodes throughout the election year. During a Labor Day campaign stop she suffered a 4-minute choking marathon. Monday&#8217;s throwdown could top out at 100 million viewers, making it the biggest political event in history. EDITOR&#8217;S NOTE: The presidential debate commission settled an early flashpoint when Clinton demanded a step-stool at the podium to add height to her 5&#8217;4&#8243; frame. Campaign Chairman John Podesta expressed concern that Hillary would be dwarfed by 6&#8217;2&#8243; Trump. The request was quickly rejected. The commission is allowing for a custom-made podium, which will accommodate the difference in stature. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>581</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>582</end>
        <start>582</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>657</end>
        <start>583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>850</end>
        <start>658</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>924</end>
        <start>851</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1120</end>
        <start>925</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1274</end>
        <start>1121</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1381</end>
        <start>1275</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1772</end>
        <start>1382</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1773</end>
        <start>1773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>518</end>
        <start>487</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>559</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>883</end>
        <start>852</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>923</end>
        <start>916</start>
    </quote>
    <title>GRAB THE POPCORN! Queen Of Corruption DENIED Special Treatment For First Debate</title>
    <uri>http://100percentfedup.com/grab-the-popcorn-queen-of-corruption-denied-special-treatment-for-first-debate/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>