<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.nass.org/news-releases-and-statements/release-nass-open-letter-to-congress-cybersecurity-elections/">
        <end>587</end>
        <start>576</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://thehill.com/blogs/ballot-box/other-races/297764-state-officials-warn-congress-against-rigged-election-talk">
        <end>2004</end>
        <start>1934</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>The&#160;National Association of Secretaries of State have told Congress to step back and let them handle it. They assure Congress that the election mechanism is secure. The data breaches have been about voter databases and NOT the election machines. The polling system is a closed system and not open to hacking. To date there have been zero&#160;occurrences.  As Written By Reid Wilson for The Hill: State officials are reassuring members of Congress that the integrity of November&#8217;s elections is secure amid growing concerns over cyberattacks by foreign actors tied to Russia. In an open letter to Congress, the National Association of Secretaries of State warns against damaging public confidence in the electoral process. The group, made up of bipartisan election administrators across the nation, says security measures currently in place are sufficient to guarantee an accurate vote count. Vote-counting systems &#8220;have their own fail-safes and contingency solutions that would make it highly difficult to leverage them for changing outcomes,&#8221; the association said. &#8220;Poll books, printed records, back-ups and back-ups of back-ups all provide multiple layers of security around this part of the process.&#8221; The association said there is no fix-all to guard against all cyberattacks but pointed out that recent hacks of voter registration systems in Arizona and Illinois are unconnected to separate systems that tally votes. The decentralized nature of American election administration acts as its own safeguard, the association said. In November, Americans will vote at hundreds of thousands of polling locations, and those votes are counted by more than 9,000 election administrators, making large-scale hacking almost impossible, it added. What&#8217;s more, voting machines themselves are not connected to the internet, providing more security. &#8220;There is no evidence that ballot manipulation has ever occurred in the U.S. via&#8230;&#8230; Full Story Here: State officials warn Congress against &#8216;rigged election&#8217; talk | TheHill</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>350</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>351</end>
        <start>351</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>391</end>
        <start>352</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>569</end>
        <start>392</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>886</end>
        <start>570</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1198</end>
        <start>887</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1415</end>
        <start>1199</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1833</end>
        <start>1416</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1916</end>
        <start>1834</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1933</end>
        <start>1917</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2004</end>
        <start>1934</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>eagle-rising</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1037</end>
        <start>910</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1197</end>
        <start>1062</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2004</end>
        <start>1917</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Rigged Election?</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/rigged-election/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>