<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/16/exclusive-twice-arrested-illegal-alien-kills-sheriffs-deputy-in-dui/">
        <end>37</end>
        <start>29</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>A Kansas sheriffs deputy was murdered on Sunday by illegal immigrants that had been arrested on two occasions already. The perpetrator was&#160;Adrian Espinosa-Flores who is 38 years old. He was charged on Monday with the crime of involuntary manslaughter. Allegedly, he was driving drunk and crashed his truck into a&#160;patrol car that had been stopped on the side of the road. Unfortunately the crash led to the death of&#160;Johnson County Sheriff&#8217;s Department Master Deputy Brandon Collins who was 45 years of age at the time of the accident. The Kansas City Star reported in the investigation. They reported that the Immigration and Customs Enforcement had made&#160;an immigration detainer on the suspect Espinosa-Flores. Detainers are requests that people be transferred into the custody of ICE. They are specifically made for the purposes of immigration violations. An anonymous source with inside knowledge of the investigation tipped off the media that the detainer the suspect had was because of allegations he was in the country illegally. The&#160;Johnson County District Attorney&#8217;s Office&#160;refused to answer any questions saying that it is an ongoing investigation. The suspect was arrested for DUI in 2001 and in 2013 had a traffic violation however ICE noted they had not been notified of these previous arrests. 41 Action News reported, &#8220;it could be considered profiling because a lot of people of all races are arrested without a proper ID.&#8221; People laughed Donald Trump off and called him a xenophobe when he pointed out all the people in the United States murdered by illegal immigrants. Surely, they&#8217;re not laughing now. This very sad and tragic incident proves that Trump&#8217;s comments about violent illegal immigrants is far truer than anyone would like to admit. However, come November when he builds that wall this hopefully won&#8217;t be as great of an issue anymore. &#160; </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>370</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>585</end>
        <start>371</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>855</end>
        <start>586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1155</end>
        <start>856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1329</end>
        <start>1156</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1435</end>
        <start>1330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1758</end>
        <start>1436</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1860</end>
        <start>1759</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1862</end>
        <start>1861</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1863</end>
        <start>1863</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>freedom-daily</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1434</end>
        <start>1331</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Another Obama Success Story: Twice Arrested Illegal Alien Kills Sheriff&#8217;s Deputy</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/another-obama-success-story-twice-arrested-illegal-alien-kills-sheriffs-deputy/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>