<article>
    <author>S. White</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://thefederalistpapers.org/us/barack-obama-jokes-about-terrorism-the-same-day-america-is-bombed-twice">
        <end>52</end>
        <start>44</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Obama just made himself out to be a grade A jerkface. The man thinks he has jokes, but after the joke he just told, someone needs to grab us a whole lot of rotten veggies&#8230;to throw at this horrid President. The man told jokes about ISIS and terrorism&#8230;and it just so happens to be on the same day that the U.S. gets bombed TWICE! It&#8217;s those kind of jokes that aren&#8217;t jokes really. You know, the kind people tell that want to be douchebags. The kind someone tells to look cool, but really just come out looking like an awful person. Yea, that&#8217;s the kind. &#8230;but it&#8217;s the timing that was SO wrong. Barack Obama was speaking at a dinner of the Congressional Black Caucus. He was surrounded by peers who non-think just like him, so naturally&#8230;he thought he&#8217;d try to be funny and ended up just looking like a total ass. Drum roll please&#8230;. &#8220;I don&#8217;t know about you guys, but I am so relieved that the whole birther thing is over,&#8221; Obama said. &#8220;I mean, ISIL, North Korea, poverty, climate change, none of those things weighed on my mind like the validity of my birth certificate.&#8221; Watch as Obama jokes at 1:55 in the video.  Now people think this joke was horrid for many different reasons. One, of course is because in the same day there were 2 explosions in the U.S. caused by bombs, and a horrid stabbing after someone shouted out two words&#8230; any guesses? &#8220;Allah Akbar!&#8221; of course&#8230; However, I think in addition to that&#8230;the man is the President of the United States. As such, I just plain expect better character from him. Maybe I&#8217;m old school, but if he is really relieved about the &#8216;birther&#8217; thing being &#8216;over&#8217; &#8230;. why is he talking about it, even if it&#8217;s by joke? Why usher in a whole new level of sarcastic, negative contention&#8230;with a non-joke by regurgitating a topic that not only is the least of our problems, but insults the focus on our ACTUAL problems? It&#8217;s bad form, bad character, and quite very unintelligent of him to do. But&#8230;why would we expect anything more from him. He&#8217;s Obama. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>205</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>327</end>
        <start>206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>551</end>
        <start>328</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>591</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>809</end>
        <start>592</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>828</end>
        <start>810</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1067</end>
        <start>829</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1110</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1111</end>
        <start>1111</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1344</end>
        <start>1112</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1370</end>
        <start>1345</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1849</end>
        <start>1371</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1922</end>
        <start>1850</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1982</end>
        <start>1923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1983</end>
        <start>1983</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>freedom-daily</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>917</end>
        <start>830</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1066</end>
        <start>932</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1358</end>
        <start>1346</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>WATCH: After America Is Bombed Twice Obama Jokes About Terrorism</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/america-bombed-twice-obama-jokes-terrorism/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>