<article>
    <author>Elvin Bartley</author>
    <mainText>In the wake of the bombs found in the Chelsea area of New York, Seaside Heights, and Elizabeth, NJ, we&#8217;ve received a letter from a Marine, known only as &#8220;J&#8221;, that wanted his voice heard, amidst the sea of political nonsense on the mainstream media. Here it is, unedited. Dear Obama, Hillary, and liberals scared of the &#8220;T&#8221; word, I&#8217;ve served my entire adult life in the United States Marine Corps, and I love this country, but that&#8217;s not important, because a man is judged in life by his actions, not his words. When you were given the task of protecting America, instead of giving people the tools to do it themselves, you treated them like children that couldn&#8217;t be trusted with their own safety. You stripped away their freedoms and promised them that you had everything under control. You allowed un-vetted, America-hating refugees that pledged allegiance to ISIS and other radical regimes and ideologies to walk freely, while they plotted to destroy the country from within. That&#8217;s exactly how you topple an empire without firing a single shot, and you&#8217;re falling for it like&#160;a bunch of amateurs. Repeat after me: You are not equipped to handle this. You&#8217;ve built your entire agenda on the false notion that fundamentalist Muslims either don&#8217;t exist, or can&#8217;t harm us because they&#8217;re on the other side of the world. Well, take a wild guess what happens when you import them to our shores and tell them that anyone criticizing Islam should be shunned, no matter how suspicious they act. It&#8217;s how you end up with attacks like the one in San Bernardino, and how you get bombings in New York City, Elizabeth, and Seaside Heights, where Marines&#160;were staging a summer run for charity, with the exact same IEDs I&#8217;ve seen used to kill my brothers and sisters while serving in the Middle East. When George W. Bush said &#8220;Fight them over there so we don&#8217;t have to fight them here,&#8221; this is what he was talking about. The fight is here, and you might as well have sent them a written invitation. If you&#8217;re too scared to say it, I will: These bombings were&#160;a textbook definition of terrorism. It doesn&#8217;t get any more clear, and every minute that goes by that you ignore it, the men willing to kill innocent people&#160;grow stronger. These attacks were&#160;enacted by those who want to literally terrorize our way of life. They hate our freedoms, and want &#8211; above all else &#8211; &#160;to control us, much in the way that you want to control our actions, speech, and political motivations. But America is better than that. We&#8217;re not children that need to be led by the hand into a den of wolves. We&#8217;re the country of prosperity, strength, and built on the idea that we don&#8217;t take threats kindly. We have the most advanced military in the world, and a God-fearing citizenry that, unlike your liberal friends, won&#8217;t kneel to evil men. We&#8217;re the real America that you&#8217;re actively trying to silence, that gets things done by working together and ensuring that anyone coming in to the country better have a damn good reason for doing it. We support&#160;the police, that put their lives on the line when disarming a bomb, despite your best efforts to call them all racist monsters.&#160;We&#8217;re the ones going to work to keep the country running while the entitled brats that voted for you go on social media and complain about why life isn&#8217;t fair. We&#160;are the people you come running to when shit hits the fan, and we will stand no longer while you try to destroy this country by kowtowing to terrorists and fill pointless speeches with nothing but empty words and lies to the America public. The way I see it, this leaves you with&#160;three options: Take action, step down, or let America run over you. The choice is yours. Just don&#8217;t say I didn&#8217;t warn you. -J &#160; </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>270</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>328</end>
        <start>271</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>510</end>
        <start>329</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>978</end>
        <start>511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1100</end>
        <start>979</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1154</end>
        <start>1101</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1489</end>
        <start>1155</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1788</end>
        <start>1490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1987</end>
        <start>1789</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2219</end>
        <start>1988</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2461</end>
        <start>2220</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2804</end>
        <start>2462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3303</end>
        <start>2805</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3547</end>
        <start>3304</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3709</end>
        <start>3548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3712</end>
        <start>3710</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3714</end>
        <start>3713</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3715</end>
        <start>3715</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>freedom-daily</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>98</end>
        <start>97</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>321</end>
        <start>320</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1873</end>
        <start>1815</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>This Brave Marine&#8217;s Open Letter To Obama And Hillary Will Shake America To Its Core</title>
    <uri>http://www.yesimright.com/this-brave-marines-open-letter-to-obama-and-hillary-will-shake-america-to-its-core/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>