<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://conservativetribune.com/hillary-had-secret-surgery/">
        <end>52</end>
        <start>43</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Speculation about Hillary Clinton&#8217;s health continues to grow after her 9/11 fainting and overheating spell that forced her to leave a remembrance service early. She has released some medical records on Wednesday as rumors persisted. However, most people still don&#8217;t believe what she has to say. The released records have caused even more speculation and wonder especially over Clinton&#8217;s lack of transparency. Dr. Lisa Bardack released a letter that showed Clinton actually had surgery in January because of a severe sinus infection. But Clinton never revealed this to the public. Doctors put a drain in Clinton&#8217;s ear in order to clear the fluid that came as a result of her infection. Apparently it made her better. People have intimidated that she likely had a&#160;myringotomy. A CT scan in March showed that she had healed up well. Bardack wrote in her report, &#8220;This scan showed no abnormalities of the brain and mild chronic sinusitis. The symptoms resolved and she continued symptom-free for the next six months.&#8221; While a sinus infection certainly is nothing to serious the major problem people have is with her dishonesty. Why keep it a secret? Why be dishonest? Why lack transparency? Read the full transcript here.   Clinton&#8217; campaign has a notable and widely publicized issue with transparency and honesty. She is well aware of the fact that many people think this about her and question the veracity of her healthy status. Thus, to be dishonest through a lie of omission seems simply stupid. Clinton is many things but stupid isn&#8217;t one of them. So why the lies? The public had a right to know about the health of the people running for the highest office in the land. It&#8217;s a perfectly reasonable line of questioning. To brush it off as a conspiracy theory is wrong, which Clinton has done. And it further shows people they have something to be concerned about. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>408</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>774</end>
        <start>409</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>859</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1217</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1218</end>
        <start>1218</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1219</end>
        <start>1219</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1566</end>
        <start>1220</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1865</end>
        <start>1567</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1866</end>
        <start>1866</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>freedom-daily</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1012</end>
        <start>860</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>BREAKING: &#8220;Bombshell Revelation&#8221; &#8212; Hillary Had Secret Surgery THIS Year</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/breaking-bombshell-revelation-hillary-had-secret-surgery-this-year/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>