<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://The report does not identify any of the immigrants by name, but Inspector General John Roth's auditors said they were all from">
        <end>802</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Weirdest thing, United States Immigration made a mistake. Just kidding it&#8217;s not weird, in fact they just caught themselves making 858 mistakes when they mistakenly granted citizenship to immigrants who had pending deportation orders from countries of concern to national security or with high rates of immigration fraud. Oopsie. Don&#8217;t worry government everyone makes mistakes and it&#8217;s only OUR NATIONAL SECURITY AT RISK!!!!! I mean c&#8217;mon guys, this isn&#8217;t like accidentally leaving the onion on a burger when the customer says &#8216;hold the onion&#8217;. A human being and their paperwork is much larger than a burger. Homeland Security Department&#8217;s inspector general found that these particular immigrants used different names and birthdates and their fingerprints were missing from the database. The report does not identify any of the immigrants by name, but Inspector General John Roth&#8217;s auditors said they were all from &#8220;special interest countries&#8221; &#8212; those that present a national security concern for the United States &#8212; or neighboring countries with high rates of immigration fraud. The report did not identify those countries. DHS officials identified an additional 953 people who had been naturalized despite outstanding deportation orders, though auditors couldn&#8217;t determine if those immigrants had digital fingerprints on file or not. Roth&#8217;s report said fingerprints are missing from federal databases for as many as 315,000 immigrants with final deportation orders or who are fugitive criminals. Immigration and Customs Enforcement has not reviewed about 148,000 of those immigrants&#8217; files to add fingerprints to the digital record. The biggest danger in mistakenly awarding citizenship to someone who should be deported is that as a US Citizen they would be able to apply for jobs that require security clearance. So far 3 of these mistaken &#8216;citizens&#8217; acquired aviation and transportation credentials. A 4th person had become a law enforcement officer. For now immigration and DHS are scrambling to fill the holes in the files and implement a system to evaluate each case of the immigrants improperly granted citizenship. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>424</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>786</end>
        <start>425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1334</end>
        <start>787</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1633</end>
        <start>1335</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2123</end>
        <start>1634</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2124</end>
        <start>2124</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>freedom-daily</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>941</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1633</end>
        <start>787</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>800 Immigrants Set To Be Deported For National Security Concerns &#8216;Mistakenly&#8217; Granted Citizenship</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/800-immigrants-set-to-be-deported-for-national-security-concerns-mistakenly-granted-citizenship/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>