<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://thefederalistpapers.org/us/female-muslim-american-olympian-bashes-u-s-a-claims-she-feels-unsafe">
        <end>427</end>
        <start>405</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Well tell us how you really feel. Normally when a Muslim bashes the USA, you wouldn&#8217;t think that they&#8217;re an American themselves. Such wasn&#8217;t the case when it came to American Olympian fencer Ibtihaj Muhammad,who became the first American to compete in an Olympic games wearing a Hijab. As it turns out, she has some nasty things to say about the country she&#8217;s representing. According to her, as quoted by The Federalist Papers: [I feel unsafe] all the time. I had someone follow me home from practice and try to report me to police.&#160;And this is right on 28th and 7th in New York City&#8230; I want people to know that as hard as [these racist incidents] are on me, they don&#8217;t come even close to things we&#8217;ve seen like the shooting in North Carolina or the rhetoric around the Khan family at the DNC. It&#8217;s ridiculous and we as a country have to change and I feel like this is our moment.&#8221; How terrible &#8211; but let&#8217;s not pretend that we live in an &#8220;Islamophobic&#8221; country when the number of hate crimes against Jews is a multiple of those against Muslims.  If she thinks America is so terrible, why doesn&#8217;t she move to a Muslim country? I think we all know the answer &#8211; because no where else in the world do Muslims have it as good as they do in America. She&#8217;s not going to be stoned to death in America. She&#8217;s not going to have her genitals mutilated in America. She&#8217;s not going to be prevented from drinking alcohol in America. She&#8217;s not going to have her hand cut off if she were caught stealing in America. When that&#8217;s what she faces if she were to live in a Muslim country, I think she can deal with a single incident of racial profiling. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>33</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>285</end>
        <start>34</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>373</end>
        <start>286</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>427</end>
        <start>374</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>584</end>
        <start>428</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>793</end>
        <start>585</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>881</end>
        <start>794</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1044</end>
        <start>882</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1045</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1243</end>
        <start>1046</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1499</end>
        <start>1244</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1500</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1633</end>
        <start>1633</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>freedom-daily</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>951</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>838</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Female Muslim-American Olympian Bashes U.S.A. &#8212;Goes Off The Hinges About Why America Sucks!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/female-muslim-american-olympian-bashes-u-s-a-goes-off-the-hinges-about-why-america-sucks/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>