<article>
    <author>S. White</author>
    <mainText>Sometimes when you try to be clever, it backfires&#8230; it&#8217;s always a gamble. In this case though, it was more like Hillary backfired, had all 4 tires blow, and then gets out of the car just in time to get rammed by a passing ice-cream truck&#8230; The woman made an entrance to a song that was just not the right song to pick&#8230;sorta. It probably would have been fine, except CBS totally threw her under the bus&#8230; Which&#8230;what?! Anywho&#8230;get your laugh on, check this out.  Daaaaang, someone needs to buy the person who wrote that script a drink! They provided us with some good entertainment right there. I mean&#8230; AWKWARD! That whole thing about Hillary, how ironic right? However, the dialogue between the anchors themselves and the awkward &#8216;it wasn&#8217;t me, it wasn&#8217;t me&#8217; and sticking their heads up Hillary&#8217;s you know what even further&#8230; was priceless. Cowards really. So what if you read from a script, you don&#8217;t hold the thing up on air, wave it around and pass the blame over something you reported. It&#8217;s just tasteless in my opinion. She was probably freaking out, that she was going to be the next social media target for ridicule..blah blah blah. It&#8217;s sad really when you see people enslaved to that kind of fear&#8230;and when you are, that&#8217;s when you can label yourself a liberal. Everything is an issue with them, because they didn&#8217;t get told the truth often enough growing up. Hillary Clinton walked out to James Brown&#8217;s &#8216;I feel good&#8217; &#8230; someone is STILL lying to her. The woman is not well&#8230; and as for feeling nice like sugar and spice? When did Satan get a spice cabinet? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>72</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>237</end>
        <start>73</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>400</end>
        <start>238</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>413</end>
        <start>401</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>455</end>
        <start>414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>456</end>
        <start>456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>588</end>
        <start>457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>605</end>
        <start>589</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>655</end>
        <start>606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>834</end>
        <start>656</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1019</end>
        <start>835</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1134</end>
        <start>1020</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1264</end>
        <start>1135</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1362</end>
        <start>1265</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1453</end>
        <start>1363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1522</end>
        <start>1454</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1558</end>
        <start>1523</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1559</end>
        <start>1559</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>freedom-daily</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>WATCH: Hillary Clinton Makes Her Grand Entrance With The Most Unfortunate Song EVER! LMAO</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/hillary-clinton-grand-entrance-unfortunate-song/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>