<article>
    <author>Natalie Dickinson</author>
    <mainText>The story of how a group of black clubgoers were turned away at the door of a club is going viral. Ashley Ellis Sisco and a group of friends attempted to visit the&#160;Kandy Bar in Charlotte, North Carolina. They were turned away at the door and told they needed a membership to get in, but a group of white girls behind them told them that wasn&#8217;t the case. The bouncers, clearly racially profiling, allowed the white girls to enter while Sisco filmed them turning away a black man with dreads. Sisco later posted in the comments that &#8220;the sad thing is that we all work in public service. It was a group of nurses, teachers, bankers people who serve the community and work with every race and ethnicity without judgement&#8230;.and we have to go back into the community we serve and be treated like trash.&#8221; It is clear that in North Carolina, a state where support for the Confederacy still is very strong, racism is still a major part of their identity, and this kind of display of casual racism makes it clear how Donald Trump is so popular in this country. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>490</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>796</end>
        <start>491</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1049</end>
        <start>797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1050</end>
        <start>1050</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>occupy-democrats</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>795</end>
        <start>532</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Charlotte Nightclub Caught Letting Only Whites Inside In Viral Video</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/19/charlotte-nightclub-caught-letting-whites-inside-viral-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>