<article>
    <author>Grant Stern</author>
    <hyperlink href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/777013142526185473">
        <end>1717</end>
        <start>1673</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/16/trump-just-tricked-gullible-media-promoting-new-hotel-25-minutes/">
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1770</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>It only took Seth Meyers ten minutes to blow up the gullible media for broadcasting an hour-long Trump infomercial, willfully spreading more of the Republican nominee&#8217;s outrageous lies and allowing him to twist the narrative and pretend that he hasn&#8217;t been leading the&#160;birther movement for the past five years while using the occasion to promote his new hotel. After a half an hour of free advertising, Trump finally tossed the media the bone they were waiting for, a thirty second statement with no apology that FALSELY&#160;claimed that Hillary Clinton started the birther movement in the first place. You don&#8217;t peddle racist rhetoric for five years and then decide when it&#8217;s over. We decide when it&#8217;s over. And it&#8217;s certainly not over after a thirty second statement in a thirty minute hotel commercial. He&#8217;s right. Donald Trump is a shameless birther, a man who spent&#160;half a decade&#160;making racist claims about President Obama long past any rational point of interest, questioning the President&#8217;s birthplace and religion for the sake of personal attention within the bigot wing of the Republican Party. Anyone na&#239;ve enough to believe that Donald Trump isn&#8217;t&#160;a hate-mongering politician merely must look at that thirty second statement, which was immediately&#160;followed by the a concentrated effort by the Trump campaign to gaslight the country and claim innocence while blaming Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton.&#160;&#8220;I&#8217;m not sure the guy who holds fake press conferences, has a fake university, a fake foundation, fake hair, and a fake tan, should be in charge of deciding what&#8217;s real!&#8221; rips Meyers. But it&#8217;s a crock of lies, and Seth Meyers called out the Republican nominee for knowingly pulling the hotel commercial stunt&#160;which Trump&#160;admitted in a tweet. Meyers pointed out that even CNN&#8217;s anchors thought Donald Trump was full of crap while their infomercial was rolling,&#160;but they didn&#8217;t cut or break away and kept letting the Republican candidate hawk his hotel anyway.&#160;Meyers then rips into Trump surrogate and disgraced New Jersey governor Chris Christie for defending Trump while prosecutors are accusing him of orchestrating the &#8220;Bridgegate scandal.&#8221;The traditional&#160;&#8220;objective&#8221; style of coverage with it&#8217;s he said-she said equivalence is not capable of aptly conveying the factual reality of the gushing sewer of falsehoods&#160;that is Donald Trump.&#160;We who write here seek to ably analyze the news from a reasonable person&#8217;s point of view and present to you our readers what has actually occurred with a transparent written analysis of events based on the solid and established facts at hand in our detailed stories. It&#8217;s about time that the media quit giving a free pass to Trump and his lying pack of surrogates, scoundrels and birthers. If they remind the entire country daily that the Republican nominee is a racist birther for at least 30 seconds of each political news program daily, maybe it would help make up for the three billion dollars&#160;in&#160;free advertising they&#8217;ve already gifted&#160;to his vile campaign of hatred. Watch it here: </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>360</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>598</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>801</end>
        <start>599</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1099</end>
        <start>802</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1592</end>
        <start>1100</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2614</end>
        <start>1593</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3020</end>
        <start>2615</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3035</end>
        <start>3021</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3036</end>
        <start>3036</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>occupy-democrats</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1578</end>
        <start>1410</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2151</end>
        <start>2132</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2178</end>
        <start>2169</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>801</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Seth Meyers Destroys Trump&#8217;s Lie That Hillary Started Birtherism (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/20/seth-meyer-destroys-trumps-lie-hillary-started-birtherism-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>