<article>
    <author>Nathan Wellman</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://reason.com/archives/2016/08/02/penn-jillette-on-libertarianism-election/2">
        <end>102</end>
        <start>88</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Penn Jillette, most famous for being one half of magician duo Penn &amp; Teller, has shared with Reason TV about how Trump is more dangerous&#160;than anybody suspects, citing his time working with him on&#160; Jillette&#160;talked to Nick Gillespie about how, similar to many aspects of Trump&#8217;s campaign, even the fundamental set up of the reality show was based on a lie. &#8220;I mean, we&#8217;re co-workers on a television show,&#8221; Jillette&#160;said. &#8220;He&#8217;s not seeing if he&#8217;s going to hire me. He has no job. The places he could hire me&#8212;the casinos that he has that have showrooms&#8212;he put into bankruptcy.&#160;He no longer owns them. So, he can&#8217;t hire me, plus I have a job, so that&#8217;s all completely fake, right?&#8221; Jillette&#160;reported that while he was on the show, the Trump organization tried to coerce him into endorsing a potential Trump presidency. &#8220;There was a time when they asked me while I was still on the show if Donald Trump ran for president, if I&#8217;d support him, and I said absolutely not. And I believe, and this may be the most damning thing you&#8217;ll hear me say about Trump, I believe I liked him more than anyone else who was on that show. During that time I said I would not support him for president. Now, I get a call instantly. Instantly! From the powers that be&#8212;not Trump himself&#8212;saying, &#8216;No, no, no. You must support him as president.&#8217; They say &#8216;It&#8217;s going to come down to you and Trace [Adkins], and he&#8217;s going to want to know that you both support him for president.&#160;And I said, &#8216;Well, I don&#8217;t.&#8217; And they said, &#8216;Well, you have to because he&#8217;s trying to&#8212;he&#8217;s looking at the big picture here.&#8217; And I go, &#8216;We&#8217;re on a television show.'&#8221; Penn is an avowed libertarian, loyal to neither the Republican or the Democratic parties,&#160;and currently endorses Gary Johnson. Despite not being a big fan of Clinton, Penn says that Trump is an unusually incompetent candidate: &#8220;However bad you think he is, he&#8217;s worse.&#8221; &#8220;I think he doesn&#8217;t really have strong convictions and sense of right and wrong. He&#8217;s not really, really smart. He&#8217;s not stupid, you know. He&#8217;s not a dumb guy, but he&#8217;s not smart like presidents are smart. We make jokes&#8212;everybody&#8217;s makes jokes except me about George W. Bush not being smart. He&#8217;s smart. He just is. Obama&#8217;s smarter? Probably, sure. Obama&#8217;s smarter than Clinton? Probably. Almost certainly. But they&#8217;re up here, you know, and if we&#8217;re talking about it.&#160;You&#8217;re wherever you are, but you&#8217;re not smarter than Obama, you know. None of us are. Even the smart guys you know aren&#8217;t there. And Trump isn&#8217;t one of those people. He&#8217;s not someone who when you&#8217;re having a conversation with him&#8212;I probably listened to him talk for, I don&#8217;t want to exaggerate, but probably eight or nine hours. A monologue of Trump. And I can&#8217;t think of one thing he said that I went, &#8216;Oh yeah!'&#8221;      </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>196</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>354</end>
        <start>197</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>676</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>677</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1885</end>
        <start>1616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2769</end>
        <start>1886</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2770</end>
        <start>2770</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2771</end>
        <start>2771</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2772</end>
        <start>2772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2773</end>
        <start>2773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2774</end>
        <start>2774</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2775</end>
        <start>2775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>the-other-98</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>402</end>
        <start>356</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>675</end>
        <start>420</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1614</end>
        <start>815</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1884</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2768</end>
        <start>1887</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2769</end>
        <start>1886</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Magician Penn Jillette had to work with Trump: &#8220;However bad you think he is, he&#8217;s worse.&#8221;</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/news/magician-penn-jillette-work-trump-however-bad-think-hes-worse/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>