<article>
    <author>Natalie Dickinson</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/barbra-streisand/facts-matter_b_12134720.html">
        <end>59</end>
        <start>35</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/barbra-streisand/facts-matter_b_12134720.html">
        <end>74</end>
        <start>59</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Legendary singer Barbara Streisand penned an&#160;op-ed&#160;for the&#160;Huffington Post&#160;today in which she paints a distinct portrait between Republican nominee Donald Trump and Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton, disparaging the mandarin mogul for his cowardice and bigotry while praising the former Secretary of State for her strength and resolve. He&#8217;s basically a bully, but like all bullies, he&#8217;s a coward at heart. He skipped out on a debate because he didn&#8217;t like the moderator. He can&#8217;t handle the tough questions. He&#8217;s so thin-skinned that as soon as anyone challenges him, he sues them. Hillary has been attacked right and left for decades and is still standing. She has negotiated with leaders around the world to keep us safe from nuclear threat because it would destroy the planet&#8230; while he shockingly said, &#8220;If we have nuclear weapons, why can&#8217;t we use them?&#8221; And he has the nerve to call her &#8220;trigger-happy&#8221;? &#8220;Unstable&#8221;? His ignorance is astounding. Streisand then touches on the undercurrent of sexism that has dogged the Clinton campaign and her entire political career, rightfully pointing out that old white men are deeply suspicious of powerful women, afraid they will be treated the way that they treat women. So how come Hillary is not getting credit for all her accomplishments? It goes back to something I&#8217;ve felt for many years&#8230;strong women, powerful women have always been suspect. Some men are challenged by strong women&#8230; afraid of them&#8230; and some women are jealous of them. Strong women have too many opinions for some people&#8230; they prefer women who are quiet. They want us to speak less and smile more. After Hillary answered questions on national security, Reince Priebus complained that she didn&#8217;t smile enough. Well, guess what&#8230; there was nothing to smile about. As she said, this is serious business. And Trump says Hillary doesn&#8217;t look presidential? What does that mean&#8230; coming from a guy who looks like a raccoon in a tanning bed&#8230; with a flying squirrel on his head? That&#8217;s what a president is supposed to look like? A wrestler who dies his hair blonde? Republicans play dirty and their smear tactics unfortunately work. As they say, &#8220;If you repeat a lie long enough and loud enough, people will believe it.&#8221; And that&#8217;s what&#8217;s happening and it&#8217;s terrifying. We can&#8217;t allow ourselves to be swiftboated again. We can&#8217;t let that happen to Hillary&#8230; a woman who has the temperament and the experience to be president&#8230; unlike Donald Trump, whose idea of foreign policy was bringing the Miss Universe pageant to Russia. How can you support a man who says, &#8220;Women&#8230; you have to treat them like sh&#8212;&#8220; and believes such hateful things about 51 percent of the American population? We cannot allow America to fall into the hands of a narcissist who has shown no regard for anyone but himself&#8230; a bigoted and misogynist reality-TV character with no political experience and no qualms about lying loudly and often. There is NO equivalency between these two candidates. Only Hillary Clinton has the skills, the knowledge, the temperament and the compassion to lead this nation. She&#8217;s absolutely right. Donald Trump is the complete opposite of everything our nation stands for, while Hillary Clinton embodies leadership and strength in an obvious way that must make Trump feel like a chump with tiny hands.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>336</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>950</end>
        <start>337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1216</end>
        <start>951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1217</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2276</end>
        <start>1818</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2686</end>
        <start>2277</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3078</end>
        <start>2687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3306</end>
        <start>3079</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>occupy-democrats</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>808</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>907</end>
        <start>894</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>919</end>
        <start>911</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2226</end>
        <start>2154</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>950</end>
        <start>337</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1217</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2276</end>
        <start>1818</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2686</end>
        <start>2277</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>3078</end>
        <start>2687</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>JUST IN: Barbara Streisand Pens Scathing Op-Ed Blasting &#8220;Coward&#8221; Trump</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/22/just-barbara-streisand-pens-scathing-op-ed-blasting-coward-trump/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>