<article>
    <author>Natalie Dickinson</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/26/just-houston-mass-shooter-dressed-nazi-uniform/">
        <end>56</end>
        <start>26</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.phillymag.com/news/2016/09/26/nazi-flags-at-bloomsburg-fair/">
        <end>124</end>
        <start>75</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>In case you thought today couldn&#8217;t get any more weirder, a Trump supporter was busted for selling Nazi and Confederate flags at the 161st Bloomsburg Fair in Pennsylvania. Visitor Chloe Winters was enjoying the fair when she encountered a white-haired old man selling the flags of fascism and slavery &#8211; along with the inevitable &#8220;Hillary For Prison&#8221; signs, and she was absolutely appalled. &#8220;I was absolutely shocked and appalled when I saw this Nazi flag hanging at the Bloomsburg Fair yesterday. This flag represents the brutal and horrific genocide of innocent people. It stands for the hatred and destruction of a religion I feel blessed to be a part of. It&#8217;s 2016 and the world is still full of SO MUCH hate. When is it going to end? I&#8217;m sad to say that I&#8217;ll never go to the Bloomsburg Fair again, but it looks like I&#8217;m not wanted there anyway&#8221; she wrote on Facebook. As if the man wasn&#8217;t deplorable enough already, it turns out that flag-vendor&#160;Lawrence Betsinger is also a registered sex-offender for his conviction of more than 20 counts of possessing child pornography, which he doesn&#8217;t seem to believe is a big deal. &#8220;&#8220;I didn&#8217;t do anything wrong. I downloaded some shit on the Internet&#8221; he told PhillyMag.com. Betsinger doesn&#8217;t seem to understand what the fuss over the flags are, either. &#8220;If you don&#8217;t want it, don&#8217;t look at it.&#160;I&#8217;m not making anybody buy it. I guess there&#8217;s no First Amendment at the Bloomsburg Fair.&#160;I can&#8217;t see where it would be some tragic thing just because somebody bitched and moaned about it.&#8221; Deplorable indeed.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>388</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>870</end>
        <start>389</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1217</end>
        <start>871</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1527</end>
        <start>1218</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1546</end>
        <start>1528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>occupy-democrats</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>347</end>
        <start>329</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>846</end>
        <start>390</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1193</end>
        <start>1126</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1526</end>
        <start>1298</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Trump-Supporting Sex Offender Thrown Out Of Fair For Selling Nazi Flags</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/26/trump-supporting-sex-offender-thrown-fair-selling-nazi-flags/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>