<article>
    <author>Colin Taylor</author>
    <hyperlink href="https://thinkprogress.org/trump-said-he-received-a-small-loan-from-his-father-he-received-millions-5653d34aee26#.cqp75qn2m">
        <end>138</end>
        <start>70</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>During tonight&#8217;s debate, Republican nominee Donald Trump said that he received a &#8220;small loan&#8221; from his father to begin his business career. That &#8220;small loan&#8221; was for over a million dollars, and his father continued to give him financial backing throughout the early years of his career. His &#8220;success&#8221; is proof of the adage that you &#8220;need money to make money,&#8221; as he borrowed $14 million from his father and received a blind trust fund which gave him another million. Trump complained to&#160;POLITICO that&#160;&#8220;It has not been easy for me. It has not been easy for me. I started off in Brooklyn. My father gave me a small loan of a million dollars,&#8221; Trump remarked. &#8220;I came into Manhattan, and I had to pay him back, and I had to pay him back with interest. But I came into Manhattan and I started buying properties, and I did great.&#8221; Yes, poor Trump spent his early years in expensive boarding schools and was given start-up money for his &#8220;business&#8221; career, the success of which has been questionable at best, given his multiple bankruptcies. It&#8217;s hard to imagine anyone more representative of the selfish excesses of wealthy America or be more disconnected from the struggles of everyday Americans. It&#8217;s mind-boggling to understand how anyone can pretend this man cares or even understands the problems facing the American middle class. &#160;</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>466</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>825</end>
        <start>467</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1329</end>
        <start>826</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1331</end>
        <start>1330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>occupy-democrats</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>92</end>
        <start>82</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>92</end>
        <start>82</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>299</end>
        <start>292</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>358</end>
        <start>333</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>639</end>
        <start>502</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>824</end>
        <start>658</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>131</end>
        <start>123</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Trump Just Said He Got A &#8220;Small Loan&#8221; From His Dad. He Got WAY More</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/27/trump-just-said-got-small-loan-dad-got-way/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>