<article>
    <author>Natalie Dickinson</author>
    <hyperlink href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xrkPe-9rM1Q">
        <end>96</end>
        <start>46</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UnW3xkHxIEQ">
        <end>206</end>
        <start>190</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/tv/la-et-st-zach-galifianakis-clinton-between-two-ferns-20160924-snap-story.html">
        <end>368</end>
        <start>331</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/07/30/dad-muslim-war-hero-reminded-trump-sons-sacrifice-trumps-response-disgusting/">
        <end>1662</end>
        <start>1658</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/15/shame-trump-trashes-black-pastor-shut-flint-video/">
        <end>1662</end>
        <start>1658</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Comedian and actor Zach Galifianakis recently featured former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton on his&#160;improvisational comedy interview show, Between Two Ferns. Previously, he&#8217;s interviewed&#160;President Obama as well as other celebrities like Brad Pitt and Justin Beiber, but there&#8217;s one person he refuses to have on the show. In an interview with the&#160;Los Angeles Times, Galifianakis was asked if he&#160;would have&#160;Republican nominee Donald Trump on his show&#160;since his interview with Clinton was such a resounding success&#160;&#8211; and his answer&#160;is hilarious. &#8220;No. That doesn&#8217;t interest me. Doing it the other way doesn&#8217;t interest me. He&#8217;s the kind of guy who likes attention &#8211; bad attention or good attention. So you&#8217;re dealing with a psychosis there that&#8217;s a little weird.&#160;I wouldn&#8217;t have somebody on that&#8217;s so mentally challenged. I feel like I&#8217;d be taking advantage of him. And you can print that.&#8221; Between Two Ferns&#160;is known for its exceptionally awkward dialogue and for the host&#8217;s fondness for asking uncomfortable questions (he once asked Pres. Obama &#8220;How does it feel to know you&#8217;re going to be the last black president?&#8221;). Part of the joke is both parties attempting to maintain their composure and not rising to the bait. Judging from the way that Donald Trump lashes out like a wounded animal at the slightest provocation and is utterly incapable of letting the pettiest slight go without a response, it&#8217;s safe to say that Galifinakis is right about how Trump would fare on his show. But it&#8217;s terrifying to think that a man who couldn&#8217;t handle being on a comedy interview show has a real shot at ascending to the&#160;presidency&#160;of the United States; he has shown time and time again that he is temperamentally unfit for the office.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>324</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>889</end>
        <start>325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1219</end>
        <start>890</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1726</end>
        <start>1220</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>occupy-democrats</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>888</end>
        <start>548</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1116</end>
        <start>1047</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Zach Galifianakis Just Unloaded On &#8220;Mentally Challenged&#8221; Trump In Brutal Takedown</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/27/zach-galifianakis-just-unloaded-mentally-challenged-trump-brutal-takedown/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>