<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Bill Clinton defended his wife and the Clinton Foundation in an interview that aired Monday, saying he trusted the State Department to make sure there wasn&#8217;t a conflict of interest between the foundation&#8217;s donors and Hillary Clinton&#8217;s work at State. &#8220;I trusted the State Department wouldn't do anything they shouldn't do, from a meeting to a favor,&#8221; the former president said in an interview with NPR. Story Continued Below He said some donors may have given to the foundation to build a relationship with the Clintons, but most contributed because they supported the work of the foundation. &#8220;Melinda Gates didn't get involved in the No Ceilings project with Hillary because she needed to support her, or me, or the foundation for access,&#8221; he said. Clinton also suggested that his wife&#8217;s unpopularity with voters is due in part to the negative coverage of the ongoing email scandal. &#8220;They're responding to the fact that this email thing was treated like the most important event since the end of World War II,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I wonder if there's a man in America that could have taken what she's been through in the last year and a half.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>249</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>401</end>
        <start>250</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>423</end>
        <start>402</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>591</end>
        <start>424</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>748</end>
        <start>592</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>882</end>
        <start>749</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1133</end>
        <start>883</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>348</end>
        <start>251</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>738</end>
        <start>593</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1009</end>
        <start>884</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1132</end>
        <start>1021</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Bill Clinton on foundation controversy: 'I trusted the State Department'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/bill-clinton-foundation-controversy-state-department-228349?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>