<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Donald Trump&#8217;s campaign on Monday hit back at the White House&#8217;s characterization that the U.S. is in a &#8220;narrative fight&#8221; with the Islamic State, insisting &#8220;we should all be very concerned&#8221; by the Obama administration&#8217;s assessment. &#8220;For the U.S. troops in Iraq and Syria who are on the front lines against ISIS, it&#8217;s a real fight where we&#8217;ve lost real lives,&#8221; Trump senior communications adviser Jason Miller said in a statement. &#8220;Diminishing the threat the Obama Administration has allowed to materialize on its watch puts us all at risk and is another reminder that we need new leadership in the fight against radical Islamic terrorism. Hillary Clinton has backed President Obama&#8217;s failed ISIS strategy to the hilt, and voters should know whether she too shares the White House&#8217;s troubling assessment of the situation.&#8221; Story Continued Below In an interview with CNN&#8217;s Chris Cuomo on Monday, White House press secretary Josh Earnest pointed to the ongoing battle against the Islamic State as a &#8220;narrative fight.&#8221; &#8220;When it comes to ISIL, we are in a fight, a narrative fight, with them. A narrative battle,&#8221; Earnest said. &#8220;And what ISIL wants to do is they want to project that they are an organization that is representing Islam in a fight and a war against the West, and a war against the United States. That is a bankrupt false narrative. It&#8217;s a mythology, and we have made progress in debunking that mythology.&#8221; During his phone interview with Fox News on Monday, Trump seemingly suggested that law enforcement officials should profile Muslims to stop terrorist attacks, a remark that came in response to the bombing in New York on Saturday that injured 29 people, and again hammered President Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton for refusing to call out &#8220;radical Islamic terrorism.&#8221; &#8220;Here&#8217;s another element of this fight,&#8221; Earnest added. &#8220;We can&#8217;t play into this narrative that somehow the United States or the West is against &#8212; is fighting against the Muslim religion.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>230</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>820</end>
        <start>231</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>842</end>
        <start>821</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>843</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1415</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1784</end>
        <start>1416</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1972</end>
        <start>1785</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>119</end>
        <start>104</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>187</end>
        <start>156</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>357</end>
        <start>232</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>819</end>
        <start>430</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1012</end>
        <start>996</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1106</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1414</end>
        <start>1123</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>637</end>
        <start>611</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1823</end>
        <start>1786</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1971</end>
        <start>1841</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Trump's camp accuses Obama aide of downplaying terror threat</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/terror-threat-new-york-trump-obama-228353?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>