<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton on Tuesday warned that the nearly 50-day sprint to Election Day will impact far more than just the next four or eight years. Making an appeal to black voters during an interview on the &#8220;Steve Harvey Morning Show,&#8221; Clinton stressed that voters can&#8217;t sit this one out. Story Continued Below &#8220;Every issue they care about is at stake in this election,&#8221; Clinton said. &#8220;This is not: &#8216;Oh, you know, a little here, a little there. We can &#8212; you know, we can take it, no matter who wins.&#8217; No. The next 50 days will determine the next 50 years, and I say that absolutely seriously.&#8221; The former secretary of state said she hopes everyone is registered to vote and directed listeners to a website to find out whether they&#8217;re registered &#8220;because I need you.&#8221; &#8220;We gotta stand up and be counted in this election,&#8221; she added. Clinton&#8217;s comments come after President Barack Obama made an appeal on Clinton's and his own behalf in an address to the Congressional Black Caucus Foundation on Saturday. &#8220;My name may not be on the ballot, but our progress is on the ballot,&#8221; Obama said. &#8220;Tolerance is on the ballot. Democracy is on the ballot. Justice is on the ballot. Good schools are on the ballot. Ending mass incarceration, that&#8217;s on the ballot right now.&#8221; But up next on the docket is the first presidential debate between Clinton and Trump on Monday in New York, where the former senator expects to absorb a bunch of body blows from an aggressive foe. &#8220;I am going to do my very best to communicate as clearly and fearlessly as I can in the face of the insults and the attacks and the bullying and bigotry that we&#8217;ve seen coming from my opponent,&#8221; she said. &#8220;You know, I can take it, Steve. I can take that kind of stuff. I&#8217;ve been at this and, you know, I understand it&#8217;s a contact sport.&#8221; What Clinton won&#8217;t take, though, is any insults toward anyone else. &#8220;You know, his attacks on African-Americans and immigrants and Muslims and women and people with disabilities, it&#8217;s just &#8212; it&#8217;s just something we cannot tolerate,&#8221; she said. As Clinton wrapped up her interview, Trump taunted her on Twitter: &#8220;Hillary Clinton is taking the day off again, she needs the rest. Sleep well Hillary &#8212; see you at the debate!&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>140</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>282</end>
        <start>141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>304</end>
        <start>283</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>587</end>
        <start>305</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>760</end>
        <start>588</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>824</end>
        <start>761</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>996</end>
        <start>825</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1254</end>
        <start>997</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1451</end>
        <start>1255</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1789</end>
        <start>1452</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2031</end>
        <start>1790</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2209</end>
        <start>2032</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>228</end>
        <start>202</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>363</end>
        <start>306</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>586</end>
        <start>380</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>759</end>
        <start>740</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>812</end>
        <start>762</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1066</end>
        <start>998</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1253</end>
        <start>1081</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1645</end>
        <start>1453</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1788</end>
        <start>1658</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2020</end>
        <start>1859</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2208</end>
        <start>2100</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Clinton: &#8216;The next 50 days will determine the next 50 years&#8217;</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-whats-at-stake-in-2016-election-228404?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>