<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Republican vice presidential candidate Mike Pence called the outrage surrounding a social media post from his running mate&#8217;s son &#8220;remarkable,&#8221; especially when compared to Hillary Clinton&#8217;s proposals on immigration and national security. Donald Trump Jr. posted an image to Twitter on Monday night with a bowl of Skittles and the message &#8220;If I had a bowl of skittles and I told you that just three would kill you. Would you take a handful? That&#8217;s our Syrian refugee problem.&#8221; Along with the image, Trump Jr. wrote &#8220;This image says it all. Let's end the politically correct agenda that doesn't put America first. #trump2016.&#8221; Story Continued Below The message from the son of the Republican presidential nominee almost immediately drew criticisms of racism. The Skittles metaphor is similar to one that white supremacists have used in the past, but Pence dismissed the criticism in an interview Tuesday with MSNBC&#8217;s Kelly O&#8217;Donnell. &#8220;It is remarkable to me to see the level of outrage about a metaphor used by Don Jr. when Hillary Clinton is calling for a 550 percent increase in the Syrian refugee program,&#8221; Pence said. &#8220;All the while our FBI and public safety officials tell us we can't know for sure who those people are coming into this country.&#8221; Trump campaign senior communications adviser Jason Miller echoed that comparison in a statement Tuesday afternoon, calling Trump Jr. "a tremendous asset to the campaign." "America has become less safe under Hillary Clinton and Barack Obama, and Clinton's planned 550 percent increase in Syrian refugees is a dangerous proposal that will put American lives at risk," Miller's statement read. "Speaking the truth might upset those who would rather be politically correct than safe, but the American people want a change, and only Donald Trump will do what's needed to protect us."</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>236</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>623</end>
        <start>237</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>645</end>
        <start>624</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>930</end>
        <start>646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1248</end>
        <start>931</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1827</end>
        <start>1420</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>141</end>
        <start>130</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>473</end>
        <start>338</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>622</end>
        <start>514</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1105</end>
        <start>932</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1247</end>
        <start>1120</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Pence calls outrage over Trump Jr.'s Skittles tweet 'remarkable'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-skittles-mike-pence-reaction-228419?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>