<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu poked fun at President Barack Obama&#8217;s golf obsession Wednesday as he extended an invitation to the president to visit him in Israel. &#8220;As you conclude your presidency, I know you&#8217;re gonna be busy with many, many things &#8212; much more than improving what I hear is a terrific golf game,&#8221; Netanyahu said to Obama, as the two appeared before the media, with a backdrop of American and Israeli flags, after meeting on the sidelines of the U.N. General Assembly in New York. &#8220;Your voice, your influential voice, will be heard for many decades, and I know you&#8217;ll continue to support Israel's right to defend itself and its right to thrive as a Jewish state.&#8221; Story Continued Below &#8220;So I want you to know, Barack, that you&#8217;ll always be a welcome guest in Israel,&#8221; the prime minister continued. &#8220;And, by the way, I don&#8217;t play golf, but right next to my home in Caesarea in Israel is a terrific golf course.&#8221; Obama responded in jest, remarking as they shook hands that the pair will &#8220;set up a tee time.&#8221; &#8220;I guarantee you I will visit Israel often because it is a beautiful country with beautiful people, and Michelle and the girls, I think, resent the fact that I have not taken them on most of these trips,&#8221; Obama added. &#8220;So they&#8217;re insistent that I do take them, of course. They will appreciate the fact that the next time I visit Israel I won&#8217;t have to sit in bilats but instead can enjoy the sights and sounds of a remarkable country.&#8221; While the two heads of state have a strained relationship, both were all smiles Wednesday as they touted the &#8220;unbreakable&#8221; bond the U.S. shares with Israel. &#8220;As Prime Minister Netanyahu mentioned, the bond between the United States and Israel is unbreakable,&#8221; Obama said. &#8220;It is based on common values, family ties, a recognition that a Jewish state of Israel is one of our most important allies and a guiding principle throughout my presidency. One that I&#8217;ve expressed often to the prime minister is that it is important for America&#8217;s national security to ensure that we have a safe and secure Israel, one that can defend itself.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>174</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>690</end>
        <start>175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>712</end>
        <start>691</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>937</end>
        <start>713</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1032</end>
        <start>938</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1468</end>
        <start>1033</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1625</end>
        <start>1469</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2100</end>
        <start>1626</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>323</end>
        <start>176</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>689</end>
        <start>509</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>793</end>
        <start>714</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>936</end>
        <start>826</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1031</end>
        <start>1013</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1236</end>
        <start>1034</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1467</end>
        <start>1252</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1590</end>
        <start>1579</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1727</end>
        <start>1627</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2099</end>
        <start>1742</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Netanyahu pokes at Obama's 'terrific golf game'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/benjamin-netanyahu-obama-golf-228481?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>