<article>
    <author />
    <hyperlink href="http://www.univision.com/noticias/la-familia-crece">
        <end>1153</end>
        <start>1135</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>News Corp. executive Raju Narisetti will become CEO of Gizmodo Media Group, the new name for the group of six news sites that Univision purchased from Gawker Media in August, the Spanish-language broadcaster announced on Wednesday. Narisetti, currently the senior V.P. of strategy for News Corp., will join Univision late next month. As CEO, Narisetti will essentially replace Nick Denton, the founder and former CEO of Gawker Media who did not join Univision. Gizmodo Media Group president Heather Dietrick, deputy general counsel Courtenay O'Connor and executive editor John Cook will report to Narisetti. In turn, Narisetti will report to Felipe Holguin, the president and COO of Fusion Media Group &#8212; Univision's digital media division, which Gizmodo Media Group is a part of &#8212; and Isaac Lee, Univision's chief news, entertainment and digital officer. Story Continued Below Univision is also experimenting with ways of integrating content from the six Gizmodo sites &#8212; Gizmodo, Jezebel, Deadspin, Lifehacker, Jalopnik and Kotaku &#8212; with its other digital media properties. The company recently created a Spanish-language destination, "La familia crece" ("The family grows"), to host Spanish-language versions of select articles from the six Gizmodo sites.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>333</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>854</end>
        <start>334</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>876</end>
        <start>855</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1256</end>
        <start>877</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <title>Univision hires News Corp.'s Raju Narisetti to lead Gawker properties</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/media/story/2016/09/univision-hires-news-corps-raju-narisetti-to-lead-gawker-properties-004778?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>