<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Donald Trump Jr. defended comparing the candy Skittles to Syrian refugees Thursday, saying he was surprised by the reaction his tweet caused and explained he was simply making a metaphor "for risk and probability." &#8220;We have to be careful about those things,&#8221; he said in video posted to social media by CNN. Story Continued Below When asked if he&#8217;s concerned about being a distraction for the campaign, he said, &#8220;I&#8217;m not trying to be a distraction, I&#8217;m trying to point out things that have to be said, I think,&#8221; "People will today make what they want of anything, and they see the worse in everything, and they look for a subtext that doesn&#8217;t exist,&#8221; he said from a campaign stop in Boise, adding, &#8220;For me, you know, I guess I&#8217;m a straightforward guy. You know? I don&#8217;t deal in micro-aggressions where it takes a special kind of person to find whatever message they&#8217;re looking for.&#8221; He further defended his controversial remarks by saying, &#8220;If a metaphor offends someone, I can understand that and maybe that&#8217;s the world we live in today, but I&#8217;m not comparing someone to candy, I&#8217;m using it as a &#8211; it&#8217;s a statistical thing. We have to be careful who let into this country. You&#8217;ve seen what&#8217;s going on in Europe &#8211; and this is not just about terrorists, it&#8217;s about the rape statistics that have gone on there.&#8221; On Monday, Trump, Jr. tweeted a photo of a bowl of skittles captioned, &#8220;If I had a bowl of skittles and told you three would kill you. Would you take a handful? That&#8217;s our Syrian refugee problem.&#8221; A large social media backlash ensued, and he was heavily criticized for likening refugees to the fruit candy. Skittles parent company Wrigley also denounced the tweet.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>214</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>306</end>
        <start>215</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>328</end>
        <start>307</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>510</end>
        <start>329</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>881</end>
        <start>511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1308</end>
        <start>882</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1505</end>
        <start>1309</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1673</end>
        <start>1506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>257</end>
        <start>216</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>509</end>
        <start>412</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>880</end>
        <start>698</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1307</end>
        <start>940</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1504</end>
        <start>1381</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Donald Trump Jr. defends Skittles tweet: 'I&#8217;m not comparing someone to candy'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/donald-trump-jr-skittles-explains-228532?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>