<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>President Barack Obama joked Thursday that actor Morgan Freeman couldn&#8217;t make it to a White House ceremony for National Medals of the Arts and Humanities recipients because he &#8220;undoubtedly is off playing a black president again.&#8221; &#8220;He never lets me have my moment,&#8221; the president added once the laughter subsided. Story Continued Below Obama also quipped that Thursday&#8217;s medal recipients included NPR host Terry Gross &#8220;and a whole bunch of people who Terry Gross has interviewed.&#8221; Legendary comedy writer and director Mel Brooks got top billing at the ceremony, which also honored chef Jose Andres, jazz musician Wynton Marsalis and author Sandra Cisneros, among others. &#8220;As Mel Brooks once said to his writers on 'Blazing Saddles,' which is a great film, &#8216;Write anything you want because we&#8217;ll never be heard from again. We will all be arrested for this movie,&#8217;&#8221; the president said in his introductory remarks. &#8220;Now to be fair, Mel also said, a little more eloquently, that every human being has hundreds of separate people living inside his skin and the talent of a writer is his ability to give them their separate names, identities, personalities and have them relate to other characters living within him,&#8221; Obama continued. &#8220;And that I think, is [what] the arts and humanities do: They lift up our identities and make us see ourselves in each other.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>229</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>312</end>
        <start>230</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>334</end>
        <start>313</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>669</end>
        <start>335</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>910</end>
        <start>670</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1354</end>
        <start>911</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>228</end>
        <start>177</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>263</end>
        <start>231</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>478</end>
        <start>418</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>861</end>
        <start>671</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1209</end>
        <start>912</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1353</end>
        <start>1229</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Obama jokes: Morgan Freeman 'off playing a black president again'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/obama-arts-humanities-medals-morgan-freeman-terry-gross-228536?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>