<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Former Virginia Gov. Bob McDonnell, whose conviction on corruption charges was overturned by the Supreme Court last June, told MSNBC&#8217;s &#8220;Morning Joe&#8221; on Friday that &#8220;I&#8217;ve got my PhD in suffering.&#8221; &#8220;You learn more in life through suffering than you do success, and I&#8217;ve learned a lot,&#8221; the former Virginia governor told host Mika Brzezinski. Story Continued Below McDonnell, once considered a candidate to join the 2012 Republican presidential ticket as Mitt Romney&#8217;s running mate, was convicted in 2014 on 11 corruption-related felony counts stemming from the over $175,000 in gifts and loans the former governor and his wife accepted from Virginia businessman Johnnie Williams. Those gifts included vacations, designer clothing and a Rolex watch. But McDonnell contended that those gifts and loans had never prompted him to provide any special treatment for Williams. On Friday, McDonnell said &#8220;there was never any quo&#8221; in the quid pro quo case that the prosecution built against him. The governor&#8217;s conviction was overturned unanimously by the Supreme Court last June. Chief Justice John Roberts, who wrote the court&#8217;s opinion in the decision, said prosecutors had relied on a &#8220;boundless interpretation of the federal bribery statute&#8221; and added that &#8220;setting up a meeting, calling another public official, or hosting an event does not, standing alone, qualify as an &#8216;official act.&#8217;&#8221; McDonnell admitted that the case had been difficult on his family but also noted that four of his grandchildren were born during the legal process surrounding his case. Two of them, he said, were born shortly after court hearings and all of their births &#8220;were a sign to me there is a bright future on the other side of this and things are going to be okay.&#8221; He said that even though he complied with Virginia&#8217;s laws, he regretted taking &#8220;my eye off the ball&#8221; in monitoring what gifts his family members had received. He also admitted that accepting a business loan from Williams was &#8220;a big red flag&#8221; and &#8220;probably not good judgment on my part.&#8221; &#8220;I'm glad to be vacated, but I have done a deep dive of my entire life, 62 years. What have I done right, wrong? How can I be a better person?&#8221; he said. &#8220;So now that I'm on the other side of it, I think it's been an experience worth going through. I'll be a better person.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>195</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>339</end>
        <start>196</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>361</end>
        <start>340</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>746</end>
        <start>362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>984</end>
        <start>747</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1383</end>
        <start>985</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1741</end>
        <start>1384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2028</end>
        <start>1742</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2302</end>
        <start>2029</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>147</end>
        <start>136</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>194</end>
        <start>165</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>282</end>
        <start>197</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>918</end>
        <start>895</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1234</end>
        <start>1179</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1382</end>
        <start>1252</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1740</end>
        <start>1639</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1841</end>
        <start>1822</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1982</end>
        <start>1968</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2027</end>
        <start>1989</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2171</end>
        <start>2030</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2301</end>
        <start>2183</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Bob McDonnell: 'I&#8217;ve got my PhD in suffering'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/bob-mcdonnell-regrets-228572?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>