<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>For son Eric Trump, Donald Trump will ultimately win over millennials against Hillary Clinton because like Facebook co-founder Mark Zuckerberg, the Republican nominee &#8220;has been an entrepreneurial guy&#8221; who became &#8220;the epitome of the American dream.&#8221; &#8220;He&#8217;s gone from nothing into a man who&#8217;s just &#8212; &#8220; Trump said Friday on Fox News&#8217; &#8220;Outnumbered,&#8221; as Democratic strategist Julie Roginsky cut him off: &#8220;Nothing? He got a million bucks? Come on, Eri c&#8230;&#8221; Story Continued Below Trump defended his statement, saying his father has &#8220;built an unbelievable empire&#8221; and has &#8220;epitomized what America&#8217;s all about: Opportunity and working hard and being able to achieve your dreams and what you want to succeed, right?&#8221; &#8220;It&#8217;s no different than a Zuckerberg, right?&#8221; he continued. &#8220;Who went out with a great idea like a Facebook and developed this idea and built it and grew it and grew it and grew it. That is achieving something, right? And I think it&#8217;s very different than a person who has been a career politician.&#8221; The 32-year-old businessman then remarked that &#8220;in all fairness&#8221; he did not &#8220;think millennials relate to policy very well because they haven't lived their lives long enough to understand so many of the issues that influence, I mean in broad stroke of issues, right?&#8221; &#8220;They obviously understand a lot of issues as it pertains to them. Student debt, and this and that. But I think maybe taxes and things like that might be a little less significant than other issues,&#8221; Trump said. &#8220;And so I just think there is disconnect between somebody who is constantly talking about, you know, policy and this and that and then a man who built a great company.&#8221; As the conversation shifted to the Trump campaign&#8217;s social media presence, Eric Trump sought to contrast his father&#8217;s approach with that of the Clinton operation. &#8220;We're humans that are speaking to that social media platform,&#8221; Trump said of his tweets, along with those of his siblings. &#8220;Hillary has 100 people who work on her social media team. My father&#8217;s has myself. I&#8217;ve got myself. I do all my social. I was tweeting as I was walking into the room. I think that&#8217;s very, very relevant. Going on to call it &#8220;the difference between a robot speaking and a person speaking,&#8221; Trump called it &#8220;very, very transparent&#8221; before mocking the Clinton campaign&#8217;s use of &#8220;-H&#8221; in tweets to signify that the candidate herself sent it. &#8220;If you have to put H after a tweet, you're not really communicating to somebody,&#8221; Trump said.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>248</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>448</end>
        <start>249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>470</end>
        <start>449</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>704</end>
        <start>471</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1003</end>
        <start>705</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1270</end>
        <start>1004</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1271</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1814</end>
        <start>1652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2141</end>
        <start>1815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2374</end>
        <start>2142</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2469</end>
        <start>2375</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>199</end>
        <start>168</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>247</end>
        <start>213</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>343</end>
        <start>250</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>447</end>
        <start>399</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>552</end>
        <start>524</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>703</end>
        <start>563</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>749</end>
        <start>706</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1002</end>
        <start>766</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1067</end>
        <start>1052</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1269</end>
        <start>1081</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1469</end>
        <start>1272</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1650</end>
        <start>1484</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1877</end>
        <start>1816</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2225</end>
        <start>1940</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2266</end>
        <start>2244</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2316</end>
        <start>2314</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2456</end>
        <start>2376</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Eric Trump: My dad appeals to millennials because he's like Mark Zuckerberg</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/eric-trump-father-millennials-228582?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>