<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Jane Pauley will succeed Charles Osgood as host of the long-running, highly rated show "CBS Sunday Morning," the network announced Sunday morning. Osgood is retiring after 22 years as anchor of the show and 50 with the network overall. The network spent the Sunday morning show paying tribute to Osgood's life and career. Pauley will be only the third anchor of the show. Story Continued Below &#8220;Jane Pauley is the ideal host for the most wide-ranging news program on American culture, our beloved CBS Sunday Morning broadcast,&#8221; CBS News President David Rhodes said in a statement. &#8220;Charles Osgood is a television news legend &#8212; and so is Jane Pauley.&#8221; Pauley, a former cohost of the "Today" show, joined "CBS Sunday Morning" in 2014 as a contributor and has been a substitute host since. &#8220;Charles Osgood set the standard for CBS Sunday Morning,&#8221; Pauley said. &#8220;And it&#8217;s a great honor to be given the chance to further our show&#8217;s legacy of excellence. I look forward to bringing loyal viewers the kind of engaging, original reporting that has made the broadcast so irresistible for so long.&#8221; Pauley&#8217;s first broadcast in her new role will be Oct. 9.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>146</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>371</end>
        <start>147</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>393</end>
        <start>372</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>650</end>
        <start>394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>786</end>
        <start>651</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1088</end>
        <start>787</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1145</end>
        <start>1089</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>526</end>
        <start>395</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>649</end>
        <start>582</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>843</end>
        <start>788</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1087</end>
        <start>859</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Jane Pauley to succeed Charles Osgood on 'CBS Sunday Morning'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/media/story/2016/09/jane-pauley-to-replace-charlse-osgood-on-cbs-sunday-morning-004782?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>