<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton&#8217;s campaign is hoping Lester Holt is no Matt Lauer. Clinton campaign manager Robby Mook told &#8220;CBS This Morning&#8221; that his expectation for Holt on Monday night, when Clinton and Donald Trump square off in the first presidential debate, is that he call out Trump&#8217;s lies. Lauer was assailed by his colleagues in the media for allowing Trump&#8217;s assertion that he didn&#8217;t support the Iraq War go unchecked during NBC&#8217;s commander in chief forum earlier this month. Story Continued Below &#8220;We&#8217;re really focused on this opportunity that Hillary has to speak directly to the voters on the issues,&#8221; Mook said in an interview Monday morning. &#8220;But we are concerned that Donald Trump may lie, he may throw misinformation out there, and that Hillary will have to spend all of her time trying to correct the record rather than talking about the things she wants to accomplish.&#8221; Asked what he expects the moderator to do, Mook said &#8220;all that we&#8217;re asking is that the record be checked.&#8221; &#8220;So if Donald Trump lies, which he has repeatedly done in the past, that that be simply checked,&#8221; he said.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>66</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>470</end>
        <start>67</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>492</end>
        <start>471</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>873</end>
        <start>493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>981</end>
        <start>874</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1088</end>
        <start>982</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>125</end>
        <start>109</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>598</end>
        <start>494</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>872</end>
        <start>643</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>980</end>
        <start>928</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>983</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Clinton camp asks Lester Holt to fact-check Trump tonight</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-lester-holt-fact-check-trump-228663?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>