<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>While Donald Trump will top expectations, Hillary Clinton&#8217;s challenge in Monday night&#8217;s debate is to become human, former Trump campaign manager Corey Lewandowski said Monday. &#8220;What Hillary Clinton has to do here is she has to become human, and I mean that in a good way,&#8221; Lewandowski, a paid CNN contributor who is still getting severance from the Trump campaign, said Monday morning during a panel discussion. &#8220;She has to connect with people because I think what happens is people see her as &#8212; look, she knows the issues. There&#8217;s no question about that, but what she doesn&#8217;t have is that compassion that people see, and I think if she&#8217;s gonna be successful tonight, she has to relate to people on a different level, and the expectation of Donald Trump as not preparing, I think he&#8217;ll exceed that expectation.&#8221; Story Continued Below Lewandowski pushed back on the notion that Trump won&#8217;t be prepared for his prime-time faceoff with Clinton at Hofstra University in New York, noting that a similar narrative of an ill-prepared Trump played out during the Republican primary debates, yet the real estate mogul was actually &#8220;very prepared&#8221; and &#8220;dominated&#8221; his rivals. &#8220;Look, I think it&#8217;s the same preparation that he&#8217;s using now,&#8221; Lewandowski said of Trump&#8217;s primary debate prep, &#8220;which is conversation, talking with experts in their respective fields, understanding the issues, making sure he&#8217;s got briefing documents on issues that he wants to know more about, but he&#8217;s also prepared for the last 40 years of his life, and, you know, getting ready for a day like this is a big day for anybody. You got 100 million people, potentially, who are gonna tune in, and one of the next two people who&#8217;s gonna be president of the United States is gonna be standing on that stage tonight. I think it&#8217;s a big day for everybody.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>175</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>176</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>833</end>
        <start>812</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1165</end>
        <start>834</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1166</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>271</end>
        <start>177</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>810</end>
        <start>413</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1136</end>
        <start>1123</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1152</end>
        <start>1143</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1227</end>
        <start>1167</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1816</end>
        <start>1279</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Lewandowski: Clinton has to become human</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/corey-lewandowski-clinton-robot-228666?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>