<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>President Barack Obama violated the longstanding, albeit unofficial, rule against presidential headgear on Monday when he accepted a hat and blanket at the White House Tribal Nations Conference. The president was given the hat and blanket by Native American leaders as he took the stage ahead of remarks at the conference. He wore the blanket around his shoulders as a song was played in his honor, but took the hat off after just a few moments. Story Continued Below &#8220;What an amazing honor and what a kind gesture, for the honor song and the blanket and the hat,&#8221; Obama said once he took the podium. &#8220;I have to say that I am very glad that you also have a blanket for Michelle so she doesn&#8217;t steal mine. She would, too. I&#8217;m just saying.&#8221; &#8220;That was very moving, and is a reminder of the great friendships that we&#8217;ve developed over the last eight years,&#8221; he added. The unofficial rule against presidents wearing unusual hats is widely credited to Democratic presidential nominee Michael Dukakis, whose decision to wear a tank-commander&#8217;s helmet during a ride in an M1A1 Abrams Main Battle Tank has been widely ridiculed to this day. Obama himself acknowledged the rule during a 2013 visit from the Naval Academy&#8217;s football team, which presented him with one of its helmets. &#8220;Here&#8217;s the general rule: You don&#8217;t put stuff on your head if you&#8217;re president,&#8221; Obama said, explaining his refusal to put on the helmet that had been fitted for him. &#8220;That&#8217;s Politics 101. You never look good wearing something on your head.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>194</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>445</end>
        <start>195</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>467</end>
        <start>446</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>738</end>
        <start>468</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>863</end>
        <start>739</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1131</end>
        <start>864</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1272</end>
        <start>1132</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1514</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>563</end>
        <start>469</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>737</end>
        <start>602</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>852</end>
        <start>740</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1352</end>
        <start>1274</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1513</end>
        <start>1441</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Obama wears hat, breaking &#8216;Politics 101&#8217; rule on headgear</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/barack-obama-wears-hat-president-228693?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>