<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton&#8217;s running mate Tim Kaine slammed Donald Trump&#8217;s debate performance, saying the GOP nominee wasn&#8217;t prepared and near the end &#8220;looked like he was running out of gas and leaning on the ropes.&#8221; &#8220;I don&#8217;t think he was prepared, so in terms of the specifics, he offered very few specifics on any policy issue,&#8221; Kaine said Tuesday morning on the Today show. &#8220;He did attack &#8212; that&#8217;s true. He didn&#8217;t offer specifics, with the exception of his big tax plan, which is huge cuts for the folks at the top." Story Continued Below Kaine said Trump didn&#8217;t answer basic questions, such as about his tax returns, and he &#8220;showed that he was easily rattled.&#8221; He said Clinton&#8217;s best moment came when Trump was challenged on whether he said Clinton has the &#8220;look&#8221; to be president. During Monday&#8217;s debate at Hosftra University in New York, moderator Lester Holt asked Trump about previous comments he made that the Democratic nominee doesn&#8217;t look presidential. Trump responded that Clinton doesn&#8217;t have the stamina, at which point Clinton shot back that as secretary of state she had traveled to hundreds of countries and testified for 11 hours on the Benghazi killings before a House committee, among other things. &#8220;She looked like she was ready for another 11 hours of debate, and he looked like he was running out of gas and leaning on the ropes,&#8221; Kaine said.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>205</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>508</end>
        <start>206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>530</end>
        <start>509</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>653</end>
        <start>531</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1207</end>
        <start>654</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1354</end>
        <start>1208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>204</end>
        <start>141</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>318</end>
        <start>207</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>652</end>
        <start>367</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>145</end>
        <start>141</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1341</end>
        <start>1209</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Kaine on Trump: &#8216;He showed that he&#8217;s easily rattled&#8217;</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-clinton-debate-performance-tim-kaine-228765?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>