<article>
    <author />
    <hyperlink href="https://twitter.com/asvokos/status/780619672760623104">
        <end>363</end>
        <start>356</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://elitedaily.com/news/politics/rudy-giuliani-asked-if-donald-trump-feminist-debate/1624520/">
        <end>378</end>
        <start>367</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton&#8217;s decision to stand by her husband and attack former White House intern Monica Lewinsky when news of a sexual relationship between the two broke in 1998 prove that the former secretary of state is &#8220;too stupid to be president,&#8221; Rudy Giuliani said Monday night. The former New York City mayor made the remark, captured on video and posted to Twitter by Elite Daily writer Alexandra Svokos, in response to a question about Clinton&#8217;s attack on Trump&#8217;s past comments about women. Giuliani defended Trump, labeling him a &#8220;feminist&#8221; because of how he treats the women he employs, and said he would have responded to Clinton&#8217;s attacks much more harshly than the GOP nominee did. Story Continued Below &#8220;I sure would&#8217;ve talked about what she did to Monica Lewinsky, what that woman standing there did to Monica Lewinsky, trying to paint her as an insane young woman when in fact Monica Lewinsky was an intern,&#8221; Giuliani said. &#8220;The president of the United States, her husband, disgraced this country with what he did in the Oval Office and she didn&#8217;t just stand by him, she attacked Monica Lewinsky. And after being married to Bill Clinton for 20 years, if you didn&#8217;t know the moment Monica Lewinsky said that Bill Clinton violated her that she was telling the truth, then you&#8217;re too stupid to be president.&#8221; Trump himself said Monday night and again Tuesday morning that he had considered raising the former president&#8217;s history of marital infidelities as a response to the former secretary of state&#8217;s attacks. He opted against it, he said, because the couple&#8217;s daughter, Chelsea Clinton, was in attendance and he though such an attack would be in poor taste. The Manhattan billionaire did not rule out leveling such an attack at future debates. &#8220;Well, I may hit her harder certain ways,&#8221; he told Fox News Tuesday morning. &#8220;I really eased up because I didn't want to hurt anybody's feelings. So, I may hit her harder in certain ways.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>275</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>686</end>
        <start>276</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>708</end>
        <start>687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1313</end>
        <start>709</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1664</end>
        <start>1314</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1750</end>
        <start>1665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1939</end>
        <start>1751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>241</end>
        <start>214</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>540</end>
        <start>532</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>915</end>
        <start>710</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1312</end>
        <start>933</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1792</end>
        <start>1752</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1938</end>
        <start>1829</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Giuliani: Clinton 'too stupid to be president'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/giuliani-clinton-too-stupid-228789?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>