<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Republican vice presidential candidate Mike Pence said he was &#8220;so proud&#8221; of his running mate, Donald Trump, for &#8220;demonstrating restraint&#8221; during the first presidential debate Monday night by opting not to bring up former president Bill Clinton&#8217;s extramarital affairs. The vice presidential candidate told CBS This Morning that he was impressed that Trump held back after Clinton launched an &#8220;avalanche of personal insults&#8221; at him. Story Continued Below &#8220;Ninety minutes in a row of one insult after another and then Donald Trump, just completely open and transparent with the American people, said, &#8216;There&#8217;s things I could bring up, we all know what they are, we all lived through the 1990&#8217;s,&#8217; and he just said &#8216;I&#8217;m not going to do it.'&#8221; Pence said. &#8220;I think there you saw in him the restraint and temperament that would make for a good president.&#8221; Trump hadn't always planned to refrain from using the former president&#8217;s scandals as a personal attack on Clinton, but after the debate told reporters he was glad he changed his mind. &#8220;I&#8217;m very happy that I was able to hold back on the indiscretions with respect to Bill Clinton,&#8221; Trump said. &#8220;Because I have a lot of respect for Chelsea Clinton and I just didn&#8217;t want to say what I was going to say.&#8221; He added that he was going to say &#8220;something extremely rough to Hillary and her family, and I said to myself, I couldn't do it. It's inappropriate. It's not nice.&#8221; Trump had also threatened last weekend to invite Gennifer Flowers, a woman Bill Clinton admitted to having an affair with decades ago, to the presidential debate.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>267</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>430</end>
        <start>268</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>452</end>
        <start>431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>847</end>
        <start>453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1031</end>
        <start>848</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1413</end>
        <start>1032</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1576</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>71</end>
        <start>63</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>136</end>
        <start>113</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>421</end>
        <start>392</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>735</end>
        <start>454</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>846</end>
        <start>750</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>1033</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1248</end>
        <start>1142</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1412</end>
        <start>1285</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Pence: Trump &#8216;demonstrated restraint&#8217; in debate</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-first-debate-restraint-mike-pence-228787?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>