<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>While his former opponent in the Republican presidential primary spends the fall debating Hillary Clinton, former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush will be heading to Harvard as a visiting fellow. At the Harvard Kennedy School of Government&#8217;s Program on Education Policy and Governance, Bush will visit the Cambridge, Massachusetts, campus several times this fall to deliver guest lectures on topics related to education and participate in student study groups. Bush is the founder of an education policy think-tank. Story Continued Below This Thursday, he&#8217;ll also deliver the school&#8217;s annual Edwin L. Godkin Lecture and discuss &#8220;the lack of economic and social mobility in the United States and his ideas for addressing those challenges,&#8221; according to a press release announcing the appointment Tuesday. The son and brother of former presidents, Bush entered the Republican primary as a favorite of the party establishment&#8217;s donor base and an expected front-runner. He failed to gain traction, though, as voters gravitated toward other candidates &#8212; including the party&#8217;s eventual nominee, Donald Trump &#8212; and Bush dropped out of the race in February after a poor showing in the South Carolina primary.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>184</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>504</end>
        <start>185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>526</end>
        <start>505</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>792</end>
        <start>527</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1189</end>
        <start>793</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>726</end>
        <start>618</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Jeb Bush to deliver guest lectures at Harvard this fall</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/jeb-bush-harvard-guest-lectures-228793?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>