<article>
    <author />
    <mainText>Despite a lack of evidence, former Vermont Gov. Howard Dean is refusing to apologize for insinuating on Twitter that Donald Trump might be a &#8220;coke user&#8221; &#8211; instead, he claimed Tuesday that the Republican presidential nominee&#8217;s &#8220;grandiosity&#8221; and &#8220;delusions&#8221; are characteristic of cocaine use, while acknowledging that it&#8217;s unlikely he actually has a drug problem. As the nominees debated at Hofstra University in New York on Monday night, Dean &#8211; a Democrat who is supporting Hillary Clinton in the race &#8211; tweeted: &#8220;Notice Trump sniffing all the time. Coke user?&#8221; Story Continued Below The comment reverberated around the Twittersphere &#8211; it&#8217;s been retweeted some 26,000 times &#8211; but also drew criticism for being a low blow and a conspiracy theory. MSNBC&#8217;s Kate Snow, speaking with Dean on Tuesday afternoon, asked, &#8220;Why did you go there?&#8221; Dean, who is a physician, clarified that he was not actually assigning Trump a cocaine addiction diagnosis &#8211; &#8220;You can't make a diagnosis over the television; I would never do that,&#8221; he said &#8211; but maintained that Trump&#8217;s sniffling, as seen at the debate, &#8220;is actually a signature of people who use cocaine.&#8221; Then he pivoted the discussion to argue that Trump should release his tax returns and more detailed medical records. &#8220;He sniffs during the presentation, which is something that users do,&#8221; Dean said, and then attributed a series of other characteristics to Trump that he said &#8220;accompanies that problem.&#8221; He has &#8220;grandiosity,&#8221; &#8220;delusions&#8221; and &#8220;trouble with pressured speech&#8221; and &#8220;couldn't keep himself together&#8221; on Monday, Dean said. &#8220;I think it would be interesting to ask him and see if he ever had a problem with that.&#8221; &#8220;I just was struck by the sniffing and then by his behavior, which all sort of came together, these four symptoms,&#8221; Dean continued. &#8220;You know, do I think he has a cocaine habit? I think it's unlikely that you could mount a presidential campaign at 70 years old with a cocaine habit, but it&#8217;s striking.&#8221; Snow pushed back, comparing Dean&#8217;s comments to theories propagated by Trump surrogate Rudy Giuliani earlier in the race, questioning Clinton&#8217;s health. &#8220;You don&#8217;t see the parallel?&#8221; she asked. &#8220;Donald Trump has not only not made his tax returns public, he&#8217;s also not made his medical history public in any meaningful way,&#8221; Dean responded. &#8220;Hillary Clinton has done that and has answered any question that Giuliani may want to raise.&#8221; And, Dean told Snow, he has no plans to apologize for the comment, or delete the tweet. &#8220;I don&#8217;t think this is a ridiculous idea. Something funny was going on with Trump last night. Do I think it was cocaine? Probably not,&#8221; he said. &#8220;This guy&#8217;s already proving himself to be unstable. The question is, why is he unstable?&#8221; Republican National Committee chief strategist Sean Spicer said on MSNBC on Tuesday that it was &#8220;pretty pathetic and unreal&#8221; for &#8220;someone who has been a governor, a presidential candidate and, most importantly, a medical doctor to make that prognosis with no fact.&#8221;</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>361</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>560</end>
        <start>362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>582</end>
        <start>561</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>835</end>
        <start>583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1259</end>
        <start>836</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1663</end>
        <start>1260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1966</end>
        <start>1664</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2158</end>
        <start>1967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2399</end>
        <start>2159</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2722</end>
        <start>2400</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2988</end>
        <start>2723</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>politico</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>151</end>
        <start>142</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>238</end>
        <start>227</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>254</end>
        <start>245</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>559</end>
        <start>513</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>834</end>
        <start>813</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1016</end>
        <start>946</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1141</end>
        <start>1091</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1329</end>
        <start>1261</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1444</end>
        <start>1419</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1466</end>
        <start>1454</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>254</end>
        <start>245</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1514</end>
        <start>1485</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1551</end>
        <start>1521</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1662</end>
        <start>1576</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1778</end>
        <start>1665</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1965</end>
        <start>1797</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2146</end>
        <start>2119</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2287</end>
        <start>2160</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2398</end>
        <start>2306</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2622</end>
        <start>2489</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2721</end>
        <start>2634</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2846</end>
        <start>2820</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2987</end>
        <start>2853</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Howard Dean stands behind Trump 'coke user' tweet</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/howard-dean-donald-trump-cocaine-tweet-228806?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>