<article>
    <author>Greg Campbell</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.breitbart.com/milo/2016/09/20/milo-university-houston-criminilaze-black-lives-matter/">
        <end>724</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Make no mistake: the political differences ripping America apart are not merely political ones, but cultural ones as well. We are a culture at war with ourselves. We are separated into the &#8220;victim&#8221; role and the supposed &#8220;oppressor&#8221; role. Straights, whites and Christians are alleged to be the oppressors of all others and a new breed of radicalism has crept up to instill social warfare against these groups to further a self-pitying social and political agenda.   Black Lives Matter is a domestic hate group that furthers hatred for whites and for police officers in a way that the KKK has fostered hatred for minorities. Now, according to outspoken conservative Milo Yiannopoulos, it&#8217;s time to criminalize this hate group. &#8220;The left does this insane sleight of hand where they try to suggest not liking Black Lives Matter is the same thing as hating black people,&#8221; he said during his visit to the University of Houston for his &#8220;Dangerous Faggot&#8221; tour. &#8220;No one is stupid enough to believe that but they keep doing it,&#8221; he added. Yiannopoulos admitted that there are problems plaguing black communities, but suggested that BLM is not the solution, saying that a &#8220;violent movement that throws its toys out the pram and leaves black communities in ruins is [not] the answer to those problems.&#8221; &#8220;We are entering the black power phase of Black Lives Matter existence and it is crossing over into a terrorist organization. It&#8217;s time to criminalize it,&#8221; he stated. While it would be unconstitutional and wrong to criminalize political speech of any kind, we cannot escape the precedent that is already in place. The KKK is (thankfully) a tattered shred of what it used to be in terms of organization after it was ruled that their urging of violence in the name of hatred was a conspiratorial enterprise to commit lawlessness. While any bigot &#8211; black or white &#8211; should be free to spout off their nonsense, it is time to delegitimize these racists by holding them responsible for the violent conduct they encourage and urge.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>462</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>463</end>
        <start>463</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>464</end>
        <start>464</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>724</end>
        <start>465</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>953</end>
        <start>725</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1029</end>
        <start>954</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1291</end>
        <start>1030</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1458</end>
        <start>1292</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1819</end>
        <start>1459</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2016</end>
        <start>1820</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2017</end>
        <start>2017</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2018</end>
        <start>2018</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2019</end>
        <start>2019</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>right-wing-news</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>196</end>
        <start>190</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>230</end>
        <start>221</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>865</end>
        <start>726</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>946</end>
        <start>930</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1018</end>
        <start>955</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1290</end>
        <start>1163</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1446</end>
        <start>1293</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Milo Yiannopoulos: It&#8217;s Time To Criminalize Black Lives Matter [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/milo-yiannopoulos-time-criminalize-black-lives-matter/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>