<article>
    <author>Lisa Smith</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.thepoliticalinsider.com/breaking-trumps-pick-attorney-general-leaked-hillarys-wost-nightmare/">
        <end>182</end>
        <start>156</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Now that Donald is our official Republican candidate, and hopefully soon to be President, we can see who he will choose to fill his cabinet with. It may be Hillary&#8217;s worst nightmare, and every Republican&#8217;s dream come true! Leave it to Trump to hire the best.  During a recent interview, Dr. Carson made a huge announcement about who he believes will be Trump&#226;&#128;&#153;s Attorney General: Senator Ted Cruz (R-TX). He is a tough attorney and would be an ideal candidate to prosecute Hillary Clinton for her crimes! Ben Carson on Wednesday floated Ted Cruz as a possible attorney general in a Donald Trump administration, noting that it could allow Cruz to prosecute Hillary Clinton. &#226;&#128;&#156;I think he would be terrific on the Supreme Court, or I think he would be a terrific attorney general. Or he could be both,&#226;&#128;&#157; Carson told Fox News Radio&#226;&#128;&#153;s John Gibson. Carson was asked whether it would be &#226;&#128;&#156;smart&#226;&#128;&#157; for Trump, now the presumptive GOP nominee, to nominate Cruz to the Supreme Court. &#226;&#128;&#156;He could be attorney general first, you know, go ahead and prosecute Hillary, and then go on the Supreme Court,&#226;&#128;&#157; Carson added. Carson admitted that there are &#226;&#128;&#156;deep wounds&#226;&#128;&#157; though and it may &#226;&#128;&#156;take a little while for that to occur.&#226;&#128;&#157; Via The Hill It&#226;&#128;&#153;s clear that Dr. Carson&#226;&#128;&#153;s opinion is respected by Trump, and this endorsement of Cruz will certainly make the appointment more likely to happen. In addition, it would be a terrific way for Trump to work with fellow conservatives who he previously went to battle with. This has Hillary fraught with nerves! Either she wins, or she gets shipped to jail. It seems odd though doesn&#8217;t it? She goes to jail or gets a highly respectable job? What is wrong with America?!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>258</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>259</end>
        <start>259</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>505</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>847</end>
        <start>506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>979</end>
        <start>848</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1111</end>
        <start>980</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1236</end>
        <start>1112</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1511</end>
        <start>1237</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1707</end>
        <start>1512</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>right-wing-news</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1511</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>BREAKING: Trump&#8217;s Attorney General Pick Leaked- Not Who You Think It Is&#8230;</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/05/05/breaking-trumps-attorney-general-pick-leaked-not-who-you-think-it-is/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>