<article>
    <author>Miss CJ</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.jpost.com/Israel-News/Benjamin-Netanyahu/Netanyahu-We-wont-accept-any-attempt-by-UN-to-dictate-terms-to-Israel-468464">
        <end>890</end>
        <start>863</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/saudi-women-are-tweeting-about-their-life-under-male-guardianship-and-it-is-brutally-heartbreaking/">
        <end>2614</end>
        <start>2578</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>It almost pains me to say it, but Israel probably has the ONLY leader in the world in possession of an Actual Spine. Don&#8217;t get me wrong &#8211; Benjamin Netanyahu is one of my all-time favorite world leaders. I only wish that we had someone to match his strength, conviction, morality, and spirit. Instead, we have President Mom Jeans. Today, Bibi spoke at the United Nations General Assembly, which can&#8217;t be an easy thing for him to do. After all, an organization that puts representatives of nations who think Israel doesn&#8217;t deserve to exist in positions of authority isn&#8217;t going to look too kindly on the Israeli Prime Minister. But now that I think about it &#8211; if you&#8217;re speaking to a group of people who pretty much hate you and your citizens, you are pretty well free to speak your mind plainly. Which is EXACTLY what Bibi did today. Here&#8217;s a clip of his speech &#8211; Here&#8217;s more of his speech &#8211; Focusing on innovation, intelligence and water technology, Netanyahu said that despite the UN &#8220;deserving every word&#8221; of his previous criticism of the body, he was positive that Israeli expertise in these areas mean it has a &#8220;bright future&#8221; in diplomacy. Shortly after telling the assembled diplomats that they would soon change their voting patterns on Israel at the world body, Netanyahu openly called Arab states &#8220;allies for security, prosperity and peace.&#8221; &#8220;For the first time in my lifetime many other states in the region recognize that Israel is not their enemy, they recognize that Israel is their ally,&#8221; he stated. &#8220;Our common enemies are Iran and ISIS, our common goals are prosperity and peace.&#8221; &#8220;I hope that in the future we will work together openly,&#8221; he added, truly taking the growing regional cooperation out of the closet. In his address, just one day after meeting with US President Barack Obama on the sidelines of the General Assembly, Netanyahu also focused on the &#8220;unbreakable bond&#8221; between the two nations. &#8220;Our unbreakable bond with the US transcends parties and politics,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It reflects, above all else, the overwhelming support of Israel among the American people, which is at record highs, and for which we are grateful.&#8221; The truth is that women and minorities in Israel are the most free in the Middle East, which totally freaks out places like Saudi Arabia and Syria. They just use the UN to punish Israel for giving its citizens freedom and liberty, instead of forcing them to live under tyrannical religious extremist rule. But just for fun &#8211; compare what women in Israel can do and have done (what PM Netanyahu talked about in his speech), to what women in Saudi Arabia have to endure. Yeah, no contest. If, for some reason, I was forced to leave America and I had to choose to live in either Israel or some other Middle Eastern glorified sandbox, I would go to Israel, no question.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>116</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>329</end>
        <start>117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>625</end>
        <start>330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>832</end>
        <start>626</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>862</end>
        <start>833</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>890</end>
        <start>863</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1144</end>
        <start>891</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1350</end>
        <start>1145</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1596</end>
        <start>1351</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1729</end>
        <start>1597</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1919</end>
        <start>1730</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2146</end>
        <start>1920</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2452</end>
        <start>2147</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2615</end>
        <start>2453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2812</end>
        <start>2616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>right-wing-news</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1006</end>
        <start>986</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1129</end>
        <start>1116</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1349</end>
        <start>1307</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1501</end>
        <start>1352</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1595</end>
        <start>1515</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1653</end>
        <start>1598</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1893</end>
        <start>1877</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1986</end>
        <start>1921</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2145</end>
        <start>1998</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2146</end>
        <start>891</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu: The UN Has Become A Moral Farce</title>
    <uri>http://www.chicksontheright.com/israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahu-the-un-has-become-a-moral-farce/?utm_source=RWN&amp;utm_medium=RWN&amp;utm_campaign=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>