<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://louderwithcrowder.com/70-of-arrested-rioters-out-state/#.V-VfR_krLRY">
        <end>13</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Bus.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>Imagine that&#8230; at least 70% of the rioters in Charlotte, North Carolina were bused in. They had out of state IDs. Looks like it was well planned. I know here in Tulsa, hubby had to leave work early yesterday. We got word that Black Lives Matter was busing people into Tulsa as well. In our case, things stayed pretty peaceful fortunately. They weren&#8217;t so lucky in Charlotte. The head of the police union there came right out and said these were professional criminals that were brought in. This is the way the communists have organized these protests from the beginning. Wait for something to happen that causes outrage. Use the black community as useful tools for your agenda. Bus in outside radicals and then get your violence on. The people that are behind all this want race riots and chaos in our streets. Charlotte was a wild success for them&#8230; Tulsa, not so much.  From Louder with Crowder: Wait, the bulk of the people rioting in North Carolina are coming from out of state? Shut up. Generally speaking when there&#8217;s a riot like this, it&#8217;s all from people who are from the community, care about their community, and know what they&#8217;re even rioting about in the first place. No, no, that&#8217;s not sarcasm. Shut up. Take it away CNN&#8230;   &#8220;This is not Charlotte that&#8217;s out here. These are outside entities that are coming in and causing these problems. These are not protestors, these are criminals.&#8221; &#8220;We&#8217;ve got the instigators that are coming in from the outside. They were coming in on buses from out of state. If you go back and look at some of the arrests that were made last night. I can about say probably 70% of those had out-of-state IDs. They&#8217;re not coming from Charlotte.&#8221; I think the reason it did not work here in Tulsa is that the populace here is not nearly so sympathetic to Black Lives Matter. Also, the police officer who shot the black man has now been charged with Manslaughter. I still contend she had grounds to shoot the guy, but the charge probably diffused the situation somewhat. Charlotte has a large Black Lives Matter contingent and since there have been other events there, it was primed already for a riot. It&#8217;s not a conservative haven anymore and works well for their political agenda. These people don&#8217;t care about the facts or that black people are dying. They are looking for an excuse to riot and create chaos. That&#8217;s their goal&#8230; it&#8217;s part of wanting to burn all of America down. It&#8217;s what communists do &#8211; they want their revolution and race wars and they want them now. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>488</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>868</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>869</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>895</end>
        <start>870</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1214</end>
        <start>896</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1232</end>
        <start>1215</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1233</end>
        <start>1233</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1234</end>
        <start>1234</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1396</end>
        <start>1235</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1678</end>
        <start>1397</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2213</end>
        <start>1679</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2502</end>
        <start>2214</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2503</end>
        <start>2503</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>right-wing-news</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>1395</end>
        <start>1236</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1677</end>
        <start>1398</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>779</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quote>
    <title>SURPRISE! 70% Of Charlotte RIOTERS Are Not From There &#8211; Guess What That Means&#8230; [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/black-lives-matter/surprise-70-charlotte-rioters-not-guess-means-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>