<article>
    <author>McIntosh</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/michael_jordan_blacklivesmatter_Hemp_large.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <hyperlink href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/MichaelJordanTwitter.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>The absolute legend and all-time great of professional basketball, Micheal Jordan, weighed in on the riots over police shootings in Charlotte. BlackLivesMatter may find it hard to see such a giant in the black community actually agree with common sense and stability, yes.  But they are especially going to have a difficult time choking down what he says and what he did to aid the police. &#8220;First, I want to express my condolences to the Scott family for their loss. I also wish for a full recovery to those who have been injured. In light of the tragic events of the past three days, it is more important than ever that we restore calm and come together, as a community, in peaceful demonstration and conversation, and in constructive and non-violent ways,&#8221; Jordan stated clearly. You see? He didn&#8217;t draw a line in the sand between points of view. He just drew a line between civil discourse and destructive anarchy, which is exactly what is going on with the George Soros funded BlackLivesMatter.  Jordan dove a little deeper into the conversation a bit early in a statement, in which he said &#8220;I was raised by parents who taught me to love and respect people regardless of their race or background, so I am saddened and frustrated by the divisive rhetoric and racial tensions that seem to be getting worse as of late. I know this country is better than that, and I can no longer stay silent. We need to find solutions that ensure people of color receive fair and equal treatment AND that police officers &#8211; who put their lives on the line every day to protect us all &#8211; are respected and supported,&#8221; Bravo! Bravo, Sir! That is the kind of wisdom that has held this society together for so long. Love one another. Serve one another. It really is that simple. It&#8217;s easy for an athlete celebrity to talk the talk&#8230;people are going to listen. But this is where Jordan really earns the respect due, &#8220;To support that effort, I am making contributions of $1 million each to two organizations, the International Association of Chiefs of Police&#8217;s newly established Institute for Community-Police Relations and the NAACP Legal Defense Fund,&#8221;   The NAACP? I could do without. They have done nothing to strengthen the black community, other than push for Marxist policies and laws. As for the other donation, well done sir. You are definitely a shining example of how these broken communities should proceed. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>272</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>273</end>
        <start>273</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>389</end>
        <start>274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>781</end>
        <start>390</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>998</end>
        <start>782</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>999</end>
        <start>999</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1599</end>
        <start>1000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1757</end>
        <start>1600</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2130</end>
        <start>1758</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2131</end>
        <start>2131</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2132</end>
        <start>2132</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2395</end>
        <start>2133</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2396</end>
        <start>2396</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>right-wing-news</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>757</end>
        <start>391</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1598</end>
        <start>1096</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>2129</end>
        <start>1894</start>
    </quote>
    <title>Michael Jordan Makes Statement That Is Pro-Black, And Pro-Police&#8230;Labeled &#8216;Uncle Tom&#8217;?!? [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/michael-jordan-makes-statement-pro-black-pro-police-labeled-uncle-tom/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>