<article>
    <author>Nathan Wellman</author>
    <hyperlink href="http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2016/09/19/494573314/north-carolina-governor-drops-bathroom-bill-lawsuit-against-u-s">
        <end>126</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </hyperlink>
    <mainText>North Carolina Governor Pat McCrory has given up on&#160;appealing to the federal government to reinforce his&#160;controversial HB2 law, which limits bathroom rights&#160;of trans citizens. McCrory officially dropped his lawsuit on Friday, which would have sought for federal courts to protect HB2, which has become exceedingly unpopular with many North Carolina citizens and lawmakers. Moral outrage over HB2 has taken a toll on North Carolina&#8217;s economy. The NBA pulled its upcoming All-Star Game out of Charlotte, saying in a statement that&#160;&#8220;We do not believe we can successfully host our All-Star festivities in Charlotte in the climate created by the current law.&#8221; The NCAA and the Atlantic Coast Conference have also moved their championship sporting events out of the state. Many celebrities and businesses have also practiced boycotts in protest of HB2. When the federal government threatened to withdraw funds from North Carolina, McCrory attempted to sue them. The Department of Justice countersued, intending to keep HB2 from being enforced on account of it being, according to U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch, &#8220;impermissibly discriminatory.&#8221; &#8220;This action is about a great deal more than just bathrooms,&#8221; Lynch said during a news conference. &#8220;This is about the dignity and respect we accord our fellow citizens and the laws that we, as a people and as a country, have enacted to protect them &#8212; indeed, to protect all of us.&#8221; McCrory wrote in court documents on Friday that he was dropping his lawsuit due to &#8220;substantial costs to the State,&#8221; writing that the lawsuit was in opposition to the&#160;&#8220;interests of judicial economy and efficiency.&#8221; While McCrory still supports HB2, he has since offered to repeal it on the one condition that the city of Charlotte repeals its local ordnance which protects LGBT community from discrimination. The Charlotte City Council has refused to do so.      </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>175</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>372</end>
        <start>176</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>654</end>
        <start>373</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>846</end>
        <start>655</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1142</end>
        <start>847</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1424</end>
        <start>1143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1639</end>
        <start>1425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1882</end>
        <start>1640</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1883</end>
        <start>1883</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1884</end>
        <start>1884</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1885</end>
        <start>1885</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1886</end>
        <start>1886</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1887</end>
        <start>1887</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1888</end>
        <start>1888</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>the-other-98</portal>
    <quote>
        <end>653</end>
        <start>530</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1141</end>
        <start>1112</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1203</end>
        <start>1144</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1423</end>
        <start>1243</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1540</end>
        <start>1509</start>
    </quote>
    <quote>
        <end>1638</end>
        <start>1593</start>
    </quote>
    <title>BREAKING: North Carolina Drops Anti-LGBT &#8216;Bathroom Bill&#8217; Lawsuit Against US</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/news/breaking-north-carolina-drops-anti-lgbt-bathroom-bill-lawsuit/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
<number_of_quotes>0</number_of_quotes><number_of_links>0</number_of_links><contains_author>1</contains_author><first_person_pronouns>0</first_person_pronouns><second_person_pronouns>0</second_person_pronouns><third_person_pronouns>0</third_person_pronouns><conjunction_count>0</conjunction_count><modal_verb_count>0</modal_verb_count></article>